{
    "The Apple Problem": {
        "question": "There were six apples in a basket and six girls in the room. Each girl took one apple, yet one apple remained in the basket. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The first five girls each took an apple. The sixth girl took the basket as well as the apple in it."
    },
    "The Two Presidents": {
        "question": "The 22nd and 24th presidents of the United States had the same mother and the same father, but were not brothers. How could this be so?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "They were the same man. Grover Cleveland (1837-1908) served two terms as president of the United States, but the terms were not consecutive. He was president from 1885 to 1889 and from 1893 to 1897."
    },
    "Game, Set, And Match": {
        "question": "Two men were playing tennis. They played five sets and each man won three sets. How did they do this?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The two men were partners playing doubles."
    },
    "Wondrous Walk": {
        "question": "A man walked all the way from Dublin to Cork along main roads without passing a single pub. How did he manage that? (Pubs or \"public houses,\" that is, bars, are very common in Ireland.)",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man did not pass a single pub because he went into every one!"
    },
    "Father And Son": {
        "question": "William's father was older than his grandfather. How did that happen?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Let's say that William's father was 60, his mother was 25, and his mother's father was 45. Because everyone has two grandfathers, it is quite possible for a maternal grandfather to be younger than one's father."
    },
    "The Amazing Fall": {
        "question": "A man who was not wearing a parachute jumped out of a plane. He landed on hard ground yet he was unhurt. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The plane was parked on the runway."
    },
    "Shopping Is Good For You": {
        "question": "A man got up at 9 a.m. He became so engrossed in his newspaper he did not have time to go out and shop as he had planned. At 11 a.m. he went for a flying lesson. He carefully followed all the instructions given to him by his instructor until he came in to land. He then ignored his instructor and crashed the plane killing them both. The accident would not have happened if he had gone shopping, which just goes to show how important shopping can be. Why should this be so?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man had neglected to buy a new battery for his hearing aid. The old battery failed just as he was coming in to land and he therefore did not hear his tutor's crucial instructions."
    },
    "Your Turn To Drive": {
        "question": "Two brothers were talking. One said, \"I am fed up with living in Birmingham because I have to drive all the time. Why don't we move to London?\" His brother replied, \"But that would mean that I would have to drive all the time.\" Why was this true?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The brothers were Siamese twins, joined at the side. They lived in Birmingham, Alabama. Because they drove on the right-hand side of the road the steering wheel was on the left-hand side of the car. The brother who sat on the left always drove. When they were in London, England, the other drove because the steering wheel was on the right- hand side of the car."
    },
    "See Saw": {
        "question": "A deaf man needed to buy a saw to cut some wood. He went into a hardware store. How did he indicate to the storekeeper that he wanted to buy a saw?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The deaf man says to the storekeeper, \"I would like to buy a saw, please.\""
    },
    "The Two Lookouts": {
        "question": "Two sentries were on duty outside a barracks. One faced up the road to watch for anyone approaching from the north. The other looked down the road to see if anyone approached from the south. Suddenly one of them said to the other, \"Why are you smiling?\" How did he know that his companion was smiling?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Although the guards were looking in opposite directions, they were not back to back. They were facing each other."
    },
    "The Deadly Drive": {
        "question": "A man drove to and from work every day along a dangerous and twisty mountain road. However, he knew the road very well so could drive quickly yet safely. One day, while he was at work, his car was broken into and several items were stolen. As the car was not damaged the man got in and started driving. He never reached home. His car swerved off the road and he was killed. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man's expensive designer sunglasses were stolen. He normally wore them while driving. As he came around a bend in the mountain, he was blinded by the evening sun and ran off the road."
    },
    "Another Man In An Elevator": {
        "question": "Bill was on holiday. He stayed on the fifth floor of a hotel. Every morning at 8 a.m. he took the elevator down to the lobby on the first floor, had breakfast, and then took the elevator back up to the fifth floor. Every evening at 8 p.m. he took the elevator down to the lobby and then he walked up the five flights of stairs and went back to his room. He did not like walking up all those stairs, so why did he do it?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Bill was on holiday with his wife and two-year-old son. The boy is a very lively fellow. Bill and his wife found that the best way to tire the youngster out each night was to let him climb five flights of stairs just before his bedtime. He enjoyed doing it but for Bill it was a chore."
    },
    "Growing Younger": {
        "question": "Ben was 20 years old in 1980 but only 15 years old in 1985. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Ben was born in the year 2000 B.C. So in 1985 B.C. he was 15 and in 1980 B.C. he was 20."
    },
    "The Habitual Walker": {
        "question": "A deaf man was very regular in his habits. He arose every morning at 7:35 a.m. and set off for his half-hour morning walk at 7:45. In the course of this walk he went over a level railroad crossing but he knew that he was quite safe because the first train did not come by until 9 a.m. One morning, although he followed his routine exactly, he was run over by a train at the crossing. What went wrong?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "On that particular morning all the clocks were due to be moved forward for the summer. Although he had wound all his clocks he had neglected to put them forward one hour. Consequently, when he set out thinking it was 7:45 a.m. it was really 8:45 a.m. He was hit by the 9 o'clock train."
    },
    "Greenland": {
        "question": "Greenland is a huge country covered with snow and ice. Why did the man who discovered it call it Greenland?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "In about 982 a Norseman, Eric the Red, discovered Greenland. He wanted to encourage people to settle there so he called it Greenland to make it sound attractive. It is a very early example of deliberately misleading labelling!"
    },
    "Radio On": {
        "question": "A young girl was listening to the radio. Suddenly it went off for a minute and then came back on again. There was nothing wrong with the radio or with the program transmission from the radio station. She did not touch the radio controls. Why did it go off and on?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The girl was listening to the radio in her father's car. He drove through a tunnel and reception was temporarily interrupted."
    },
    "The Boxing Match": {
        "question": "At the end of a long hard boxing match one boxer was knocked out by the other. The judges agreed it was a completely proper victory. Yet during the course of the match no man threw a punch. What happened?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "No man threw a punch because the boxing match was between two women boxers."
    },
    "The Nephew": {
        "question": "A man and his sister were out shopping one day when the man said, \"That boy over there is my nephew.\" \"That is right,\" replied his sister, \"but he is not my nephew.\" How come?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The boy was the woman's son, and therefore he was her brother's nephew."
    },
    "Barrel Trouble": {
        "question": "A man filled an empty barrel. It was then lighter than when he started. What did he fill it with?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man filled the barrel with holes! Since there was now less barrel it weighed less."
    },
    "Rival Fans": {
        "question": "One day, in a crowded room, a supporter of the Brazilian soccer team saw a supporter of his team's great rivals, Argentina. The Brazilian fan walked over to the Argentinian fan and struck him a fierce blow. The Argentinian fan who had been knocked flat got up from the floor, turned around, and then thanked the man who had hit him. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The two men were in a restaurant. The Argentinian fan had a fishbone stuck in his throat and was choking. The other man was quick-witted enough to give him a strong blow on the back, thereby dislodging the bone and saving his life."
    },
    "Coming Up For Air": {
        "question": "As part of a school experiment a girl was sent to the middle of a nearby city with instructions to collect a sample so that pollution levels could be measured. She was given a glass container with a removable but tight-fitting lid. Of course she noticed that the jar contained comparatively clean air from the school environment. How did she ensure that she excluded this air and retrieved an absolutely accurate sample of the city air?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The girl filled the jar with water at the school. When she reached the appropriate point at the city center she poured all the water out. What replaced it was a true sample of the surrounding air."
    },
    "Nuts Away!": {
        "question": "A man was changing a wheel on his car when the four nuts used to hold the wheel in place fell into a sewer drain and were lost. He was afraid he was stuck there, but a passing boy made a very useful suggestion which enabled the man to drive off. What was the boy's idea?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The boy suggested that the man take one wheel nut off each of the other three wheels in order to attach the fourth wheel. Once he had done this, the man could safely drive to the nearest garage with each wheel firmly attached by three nuts."
    },
    "The Golf Pro": {
        "question": "Although there are very few golf tour professionals who are left-handed, most clubs prefer to have left-handed golf pros as instructors. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "One of the most important tasks for the golf club professional is giving lessons. Most players are right-handed. They can stand opposite a left-handed teacher and watch and copy him more easily. It is just like looking in a mirror, so it makes learning the correct style of swing easier."
    },
    "Deduction": {
        "question": "A man suspected his wife of having an affair. One day he told her that he had been suddenly called away on business and would be out of town for a few days. He then left the house but returned an hour later. His wife was not there but he quickly discovered the name and address of her lover. How?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "He reasoned that she would have called her lover so he simply pressed the redial button on their telephone. When the man answered with his name the husband told him that he had won a prize draw and asked for the address to which it should be sent."
    },
    "The Penny Black": {
        "question": "The famous Penny Black, the world's first postage stamp, was introduced in England in 1840. The idea of postage stamps was a great success and was taken up worldwide. Yet the Penny Black was in use for only one year before it was replaced by the Penny Red. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The postmark used at that time was always black. It was therefore difficult to tell whether a stamp had been franked or not. This led to people reusing used stamps. On a Penny Red the black postmark was clearly visible."
    },
    "Flat Tire I": {
        "question": "A man woke up one morning to find that one of the wheels of his car had a completely flat tire. Despite this he set off in his car and drove 100 miles to visit a customer. He then drove 100 miles home. He did not repair or inflate the flat tire. How did he manage to make the journey?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The flat tire was on the man's spare wheel which he kept in the car trunk. The four wheels he drove on all had properly inflated tires."
    },
    "Flat Tire Ii": {
        "question": "Four college students arrived late for a lecture, explaining to their instructor that their car had suffered a flat tire on the way there. How did the clever lecturer immediately show those assembled that the late arrivals were not telling the truth?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The lecturer separated the four students, so that they were not together in the room, and asked each to write down which of the four wheels of the car had suffered the puncture. Of course they did not all say the same wheel. (The chances of them all picking the same wheel are 1 in 4x4x4; i.e., 1 in 64.)"
    },
    "Bottled Fruit": {
        "question": "We all know that there's a way to get a ship into a bottle. How would you get a full-sized pear into a bottle without damaging the pear or breaking or cutting the bottle?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The fruit is grown in the bottle. The bottle is tied onto the branch shortly after the fruit starts to form."
    },
    "The Cowboy's Fate": {
        "question": "Cowboys who lived in the Wild West led a dangerous existence. They were at risk from cattle stampedes, Indian attacks, rattlesnakes, disease, and gunfights. However, none of these was the usual cause of death, which was something routine but deadly. What was the most common cause of death among cowboys?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The most common cause of death among cowboys was from being dragged along by a galloping horse when the cowboy's foot was caught in a stirrup. This would occur during a fall or when mounting or dismounting."
    },
    "The Village Idiot": {
        "question": "Visitors to a scenic mountain village were often amused by the village idiot. When offered a choice between a shiny 50-cent piece and a crumpled $5 bill, he would always happily choose the half-dollar. The bill was worth ten times as much, so why did he never choose it?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The so-called village idiot was smart enough to realize that as long as he kept choosing the 50-cent piece, people would keep offering him the choice. If he once took the $5 bill, the stream of coins would stop rolling in."
    },
    "The Island Fire": {
        "question": "A man is on an island which is one mile long and about 100 yards wide. The grass and shrubs are very dry from a long drought. Suddenly, a fire starts at one end of the island. It is racing towards him along the width of the island fanned by a strong wind blowing in his direction. He cannot take refuge in the sea because it is infested with sharks. There is no beach, just sheer cliffs. What can he do to avoid being consumed in the flames?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The man should set fire to the ground beneath him and walk towards the main fire. The wind will fan the fire he started so as to burn out the end of the island towards which the wind is blowing. He can then walk back to a piece of burnt land and stand there safely when the main fire reaches his end of the island."
    },
    "The Sleepy Kings": {
        "question": "On one occasion King George II of England went to sleep on the night of September 2 and did not wake up until the morning of September 14. His doctors and advisors were not particularly worried by this. Maybe this was because they knew that a similar sort of thing had once happened to King Henry III of France. He had fallen asleep on December 9 and not woken until December 20. We know that monarchs in those days had a pretty easy life, but what was going on here?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The kings each slept one night only. The calendar changed in France in 1582 and in England in 1752. Previously the Julian Calendar had been used, but this had allowed a cumulative error to occur which needed to be corrected. Pope Gregory XIII ordered ten days to be dropped from the year 1582. This order was followed by Catholic countries such as France but not by Protestant ones such as England. England eventually adopted the improved Gregorian Calendar in 1752, though by that time the adjustment needed had grown to 11 days. Incidentally, the thirteen American colonies were under British control so they also changed from Julian to Gregorian calendars in 1752. George Washington was born on February 11, 1732, but after 1752 his birthday became February 22, which is now officially Washington's Birthday."
    },
    "The Portrait": {
        "question": "A man stands looking at a portrait and says, \"Sons and brothers have I none, but this person's father is my father's son.\" Who is in the portrait?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The portrait is of the man's daughter."
    },
    "Winning Isn't Everything": {
        "question": "Three friends, Alf, Bert, and Chris, played golf every Saturday for a year. The games were friendly but competitive. They all had the same handicap so whoever took the least strokes won the game and whoever took the most strokes came last. At the end of the year they compared scores to see who was the best and a furious row broke out. Alf pointed out that he had finished ahead of Bert more often than he had finished behind him. Bert countered that he had finished ahead of Chris more often than he had finished behind him and that Chris had finished ahead of Alf more often than he had finished behind him. How could this be so?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "One third of the games finished A, B, C; one third finished B, C, A, and the other third finished C, A, B. So Alf finished ahead of Bert twice as often as behind him and the same is true for Bert over Chris and Chris over Alf."
    },
    "The Reluctant Diner": {
        "question": "A businessman came home as usual at 5 p.m. He normally ate dinner as soon as he arrived home. This evening he was very hungry as he had had no lunch. However, despite the fact that all his favorite foods were available and ready to be eaten, he waited until exactly 8 p.m. before dining alone. Why did he wait?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The businessman was a Muslim. He therefore observed the religious fast for the month of Ramadan. During this period Muslims are not allowed to drink, eat, or smoke between sunrise and sunset."
    },
    "Death In A Car": {
        "question": "A man went out for a drive. A day later he was found dead in the car. The car had not crashed. How had he died?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The man drove his car to the beach to watch the sunset over the waves. He fell asleep. The tide came in and seeped in around the car doors and windows. He awoke, but with the pressure of the water, he couldn't get out of the car. The water filled the car and drowned him. Later the tide went out and he was found dead in an empty car."
    },
    "Last Cord": {
        "question": "A man lies dead in a field. Next to him is a long piece of cord. How did he die?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Incredible as it may seem, some people enjoy leaping off high buildings or bridges with a length of elastic cord fastened to them. This pastime is known as bungee jumping. The poor man in this situation died when he jumped from a high crane in the field and his bungee cord broke."
    },
    "Saturday Flights": {
        "question": "A man flew into Los Angeles on Saturday. He stayed for three nights at the Beverly Hills Hotel, then spent one night in the Santa Monica Hilton. He then flew out again on Saturday. Between the two flights he never left the Los Angeles area and he did not stay anywhere except those two hotels. How could he arrive and leave on Saturday, yet stay only four nights?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Saturday was the name of the man's private plane."
    },
    "The Trains That Did Not Crash": {
        "question": "A single train track runs through a tunnel which goes from east to west. One afternoon two trains run along the track at the same speed and enter the tunnel, one going east and the other going west. Neither stops or changes speed, yet they do not crash. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "One train went through the tunnel in the early afternoon and the other went through in the late afternoon."
    },
    "Copyright": {
        "question": "How do the publishers of dictionaries or atlases protect themselves from pirates who would copy their work?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Publishers normally include a nonexistent word or a nonexistent island in a dictionary or atlas, respectively. If it then appears in somebody else's work, they have clear evidence of copying."
    },
    "The Ransom": {
        "question": "A rich man's son was kidnapped. The ransom note told him to bring a valuable diamond to a phone booth in the middle of a public park. Plainclothes police officers surrounded the park, intending to follow the criminal or his messenger. The rich man arrived at the phone booth and followed instructions but the police were powerless to prevent the diamond from leaving the park and reaching the crafty villain. What did he do?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "This is a true story from Taiwan. When the rich man reached the phone booth he found a carrier pigeon in a cage. It had a message attached telling the man to put the diamond in a small bag which was around the pigeon's neck and to release the bird. When the man did this the police were powerless to follow the bird as it returned across the city to its owner."
    },
    "Moving Parts": {
        "question": "Two common objects carry out the same function. One of the objects has many thousands of moving parts while the other object has no moving parts. What are the objects?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The two objects are an hourglass (often used in the kitchen as an egg-timer) and a sundial."
    },
    "An Early Burial": {
        "question": "John Brown died on Thursday, December 6, and was buried the same week\u2014on Wednesday, December 5, to be precise. How did that happen?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "John Brown lived on a Pacific island close to the International Date Line. When you cross the International Date Line (eastwards), your calendar goes back one day. He died on Thursday, December 6, and was flown home that same day for burial. Because the plane flew eastwards over the International Date Line it was Wednesday, December 5, when he was buried later that day. (This could happen if the plane flew, for example, from Fiji to Western Samoa.)"
    },
    "Trouble And Strife": {
        "question": "Mrs. White was happily knitting while her husband watched television. Suddenly the phone rang. Mr. White answered it. He was angry because it was a wrong number, but she was even more angry. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Mrs. White had been counting her stitches very carefully; the number was well past 300. When Mr. White answered the phone he told the caller their phone number, 837-9263. Hearing this caused Mrs. White to lose count."
    },
    "Bath Water": {
        "question": "Some time ago, before central heating and water boilers, people would heat water on stoves. At that time a scullery maid was heating a large pan of water in order to add it to a bathtub which contained some water at room temperature. When the butler saw it he told her off. \"Don't you realize,\" he said, \"that the longer you heat that water on the stove the colder the bath will be when you pour the hot water in?\" He was right. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The water in the pan was already boiling when the butler came in. The longer the maid now heated the water the less of it there would be (because of the steam) to heat the tub and the water's temperature would not rise any further."
    },
    "The Hold-up": {
        "question": "A man parked his car outside a bank and rushed in. He held up twenty-five people and ran out with $200. A policeman who saw the whole incident stopped the man. He told him off and then let him go. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "When the man parked his car outside the bank he held up twenty-five people who were stuck in traffic behind him. The policeman told him not to park like that again."
    },
    "The Worst Sailor": {
        "question": "Jim was one of the worst sailors on board ship. He was surly, lazy, untrustworthy, uncooperative, and always causing trouble. Yet the ship's captain often said of him, \"I wish we had ten men like Jim.\" Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The captain would prefer to have ten men like Jim because currently he has fifty men like Jim. He considers almost the entire crew as useless, but is stuck with them for the duration of the voyage!"
    },
    "The Valuable Book": {
        "question": "A man had a book which was worth $40/000. Why did he deliberately destroy it?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The man actually owned two copies of the valuable book. By destroying one copy he increased the value of the other."
    },
    "Cuddly Bears": {
        "question": "At a children's hospital the patients loved to play with the cuddly teddy bears they had there. Unfortunately, the children liked them so much that the bears were disappearing at an alarming rate as the young patients took them home. How did the hospital solve this problem?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The hospital dressed all their teddy bears with bandages. Then they explained to the little children that the poor teddies had to stay at the hospital for their own health and recovery. The children reluctantly but sympathetically agreed."
    },
    "The High-society Dinner": {
        "question": "At a fancy, upper-class dinner party a precious gold coin was being passed around the table for inspection when suddenly the lights went out. When the lights came on again the coin was missing. A search of each guest was ordered. One man refused to be searched. The police were called but before they arrived the missing coin was found under a saucer. Why did the guest refuse to be searched?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man who refused to be searched was an aristocrat who had fallen on very hard times but was trying to keep up appearances. He was so poor, however, that he could scarcely afford to eat. So, while at the dinner, he secretly lined his pockets with food from the table to keep him going for the next few days. Obviously if he was searched his secret would be revealed and he would be humiliated."
    },
    "Eight Years Old": {
        "question": "A girl was eight years old on her first birthday. How could that be?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "She was born on February 29, 1896. The year 1900 was not a leap year (only centuries divisible by 400 are leap years), so the next February 29 fell in 1904 when she was eight. She was twelve on her second birthday."
    },
    "Cover That Hole": {
        "question": "A manhole is a hole which allows someone to gain access to the sewers or other pipes which are below ground. Our local town council recently decided that all the town's manhole covers should be changed from square to round ones. We are used to the town council making silly decisions, but this time they were absolutely right. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "A square or rectangular manhole cover can fall down the hole, while a round manhole cover cannot. The square cover will fit down the diagonal of the hole (unless the rim it sits on is very large) but no matter how you turn a circle it never measures less than its diameter. So for safety and practicality all manhole covers should be round."
    },
    "The Protagoras Paradox": {
        "question": "Protagoras was a lawyer in ancient Greece. As an act of kindness he took on a poor but promising young man as a pupil. He agreed to teach him law but make no charge until the student had won his first case, when the student would repay his tuition fees. The young man gladly agreed to this plan. The student completed his training, then decided that he did not wish to practise law. Instead, he retired to the countryside to keep goats. Protagoras was disgusted at this waste of talent and training and dismayed that he would not be reimbursed for the tuition. He decided to sue his pupil in order to recover his fees. If the two men met in court to argue the case, who do you think would have won?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "This is a paradox with no clear-cut answer. Both parties have a good case. It would be interesting to see it argued out in court. Whoever lost could claim to have won\u2014the student in losing would still not have won a case, Protagoras in losing would ensure a first victory for his pupil. Some believe that the most likely outcome of such a situation, if it had come to trial, would have been victory for the student. He was after all under no obligation to practise law and up until that point he had not breached the contract. Once Protagoras had lost the first case, however, he could sue a second time on the grounds that the student had now won a case and was in breach of contract. Protagoras would therefore win the second case and recover his fees. Overall, Protagoras would have won. The student would be smart to choose not to represent himself but to select a good lawyer who could win the first case for him. In that case, since the pupil would still not have won a case, he would have won the contest."
    },
    "Hand In Glove": {
        "question": "A French glove manufacturer received an order for 5,000 pairs of expensive sealskin gloves from a New York department store. He then learned that there was a very expensive tax on the import of sealskin gloves into the United States. How did he (legitimately) get the gloves into the country without paying the import tax?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The manufacturer sent 5,000 right-hand gloves to Miami and 5,000 left-hand gloves to New York. He refused to pay the duty on them so both sets of gloves were impounded. Since nobody claimed them, both lots were subsequently sold off at auction. They went for a very low price (who wants 5,000 left-hand gloves?). Naturally, it was the clever Frenchman who won with a very low bid at each auction."
    },
    "The School Superintendent": {
        "question": "A visiting school superintendent noticed that whenever he asked one class a question all the children would put up their hands. Moreover, although the teacher always chose a different child to answer, the answer was always correct. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The teacher instructed her pupils always to raise their hands when a question was asked whether they knew the answer or not. If they did not know the answer they should raise their left hand. If they were sure they knew the answer they should raise their right hand. The teacher chose a different child each time, but always one who had raised his or her right hand."
    },
    "No Trumps": {
        "question": "Can you resolve this argument which arose at a recent bridge match? Spades were trumps. Which is more likely: that a pair of players will have no spades dealt to them or all the spades dealt to them?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "It is equally likely that one couple will have all the trumps as that they will have no trumps between them. For if they have all the trumps it must mean that the other pair has none and vice versa."
    },
    "How To Beat Nick Faldo": {
        "question": "A man challenged the Masters Golf champion to a round of golf on the condition that he be allowed to chose the time and place of their contest. The champion accepted the challenge but was easily defeated by the challenger. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The challenger was a blind golfer and he arranged to play the champion at midnight on a dark night. The blind man was at no disadvantage in the dark but the champion could not see his ball to hit it. (Blind golfers do play matches and tournaments; they rely on others to indicate where their ball and the hole are.)"
    },
    "How To Beat Carl Lewis": {
        "question": "A man challenged the Olympic 100-metres sprint champion to a race over a short distance on the condition that he be allowed to choose the course. How does the man manage to beat the champion? (N.B.: The solution to the preceding problem won't help you here.)",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "He challenged the Olympic champion to run up a ladder. Since he was the fastest window cleaner in Ireland he won easily!"
    },
    "The Missing Furniture": {
        "question": "A man was doing his job but was killed because he lacked a certain piece of furniture. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man was a circus lion tamer who had unfortunately forgotten his chair when he had to face a bad-tempered lion!"
    },
    "The Dead Man": {
        "question": "A man lies dead in a room, with a cord tied tightly around his neck. The door has been locked from the inside. Outside of the body, there is nothing else in the room. Remembering that one cannot choke oneself (one would pass out before dying), how did he die?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The cord around the man's neck was a piece of rawhide which he had soaked in water before entering the room. Once he had tied it tightly around his neck it naturally grew tighter and tighter as it dried."
    },
    "The Busy Hospital": {
        "question": "St. James Hospital handled all the accident cases for the city. They were kept especially busy by the large number of drivers and passengers injured on the city's roads. To improve road safety, a law was passed making the wearing of seat belts mandatory. Drivers and passengers now started to wear seat belts in their cars. The frequency of road accidents remained exactly the same. However, the hospital was now even busier handling road-accident victims than before. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The wearing of seat belts was successful in reducing the number of deaths from road accidents. People who without seat belts would have been killed (and taken to the morgue) now survived but with injuries. Consequently more people were treated for injuries than before."
    },
    "The Fallen Sign": {
        "question": "A man was walking in country unfamiliar to him. He came to a crossroads where he found that the signpost showing the directions of the roads had fallen over. How did he find out which way to go?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man knew the name of the town he had left that morning. So he replaced the sign so that it correctly named the direction he had come from. It would then be correct for all the other directions."
    },
    "False Fingerprints": {
        "question": "A man stabbed his wife to death. He was alone with his victim before and after the crime. To throw the police off the scent he suddenly decided to leave false fingerprints on the murder weapon. How did he do it?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man put his wife's big-toe print on the knife and left it beside the body. He could have used his own toe-print but that could have been later traced to him. Once his wife was buried, the \"fingerprints\" could never be traced."
    },
    "Found, Lost, Found": {
        "question": "A man threw something away. He then paid someone else twenty dollars to try to find it but the search was unsuccessful. Later the man found it easily himself. How?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man fell overboard from a small boat at the seashore. He could not swim well and got into difficulties so he threw away the expensive and heavy binoculars around his neck. He was rescued. He then offered a swimmer a reward to dive down and recover his binoculars. This effort was unsuccessful. Later, however, when the tide went out he was able to pick them up off the sand."
    },
    "The Crippled Child": {
        "question": "A child was born with its legs so wasted that it would never be able to walk. When they learned this, the child's parents were especially happy that the child was crippled rather than normal and healthy. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "This is a true story from India. The child was born into a family of beggars in Calcutta. The parents knew that a crippled child would earn more as a beggar than a healthy child would."
    },
    "Insurance": {
        "question": "A man's lifelong ambition was to achieve a certain goal, yet he insured himself against achieving it. What was the goal?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "This is a true story from Japan. The man was a keen golfer and his lifelong ambition was to score a hole in one. But this would prove very expensive as the custom at his golf club was that anyone who scored a hole in one had to buy all the other members a drink."
    },
    "Eggs": {
        "question": "Ornithologists now agree that there is a very good reason why birds' eggs are generally narrower at one end than the other. What is the reason?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "A spherical or oval egg would roll in a straight line. However, an asymmetrical egg, which is narrower at one end than the other, will tend to roll in a circle. (Try it with a normal hen's egg.) If the eggs are on a cliff edge or other precarious place, the tendency to roll around rather than straight is a distinct advantage."
    },
    "The Guard Dog": {
        "question": "A landowner boasted that nobody could enter his orchard because of the fierce dog he had guarding it. How did a crafty boy safely gain entrance without damaging the dog in any way?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The boy brought along with him a female dog in heat. He released this dog into the orchard and the guard dog was thereby distracted."
    },
    "The Last Message": {
        "question": "A man was found shot dead in his study. He was slumped over his desk and a gun was in his hand. There was a cassette recorder on his desk. When the police entered the room and pressed the play button on the tape recorder they heard, \"I can't go on. I have nothing to live for.\" Then there was the sound of a gunshot. How did the detective immediately know that the man had been murdered?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The cassette had started at the beginning of the man's utterance. Who could have rewound it?"
    },
    "The Japanese Speaker": {
        "question": "A Los Angeles businessman took great pains to learn Japanese from a native speaker of the language. He became fluent; his vocabulary and grammar were excellent and his accent was good. When he later went to Japan and started speaking Japanese with a group of businessmen there, they could hardly contain their surprise and amusement at the way he spoke. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The businessman had been taught by a woman and he spoke Japanese like a woman. The speech intonation of men and women is very different in Japan, the masculine approach being more direct and aggressive. To hear a man speaking in a woman's style was unusual and amusing for the Japanese men."
    },
    "The Cellar Door": {
        "question": "A little girl was warned by her parents never to open the cellar door or she would see things that she was not meant to see. One day while her parents were out she did open the cellar door. What did she see?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "When the girl opened the cellar door she saw the living room and, through its windows, the garden. She had never seen these before because her parents had kept her all her life in the cellar. (This is a true lateral-thinking puzzler as nearly everyone makes the assumption that anyone opening the cellar door does so from outside the cellar.)"
    },
    "The Deadly Shot": {
        "question": "A man lay dead in a field. Next to him was a gun. One shot had been fired and because of that shot the man had died. Yet he had not been shot. In fact, there was no wound or mark on his body. How had he died?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man died through suffocation. He was covered by an avalanche of snow which had been started by the sound of his gunshot as he stood at the foot of a snow-covered mountain."
    },
    "Flat Out": {
        "question": "A driver whose car had no brakes was approaching a level crossing at 60 miles per hour while a train was approaching the same crossing also at 60 miles per hour. The crossing was unmanned and had no barriers. The train was 100 yards long and it was 50 yards from the crossing. The car was 100 yards from the crossing. Neither train nor car stopped or changed direction or speed. The driver did not get out of his car. How did he survive the crossing?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Who said that the car was on the road? The car was being transported on the train."
    },
    "An Odd Story": {
        "question": "Three men went into a cafe and each had a single cup of coffee. Each put an odd number of lumps of sugar into his cup of coffee. In total they put 12 lumps of sugar in their cups. How many lumps did each consume?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The first man put one lump of sugar in his coffee. That is an odd number. The second man put one lump in his coffee. That is also an odd number. The third man put 10 lumps in his coffee. That is a very odd number of lumps to put into a cup of coffee!"
    },
    "Free Maps": {
        "question": "At some stage between the two world wars, the British government decided that it would be desirable to produce accurate maps of the whole country by using the new technique of aerial photography. They were very concerned that the cost of the project would be high as it involved many flights, much film, and long hours of painstaking matching of photographs. In the end the whole process ended up costing the government nothing. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The aerial photography enabled a much clearer definition of land boundaries, and sizes. A tax on land at that time was based on its estimated area; and these had been largely underestimates. The new maps revealed correct land sizes and the government received more income from the land tax."
    },
    "What A Shock I": {
        "question": "A man woke up. He lit a match. He saw something and died of shock. What was going on?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man was a prisoner who had been condemned to a very long jail sentence. He paid the prison undertaker to help him escape. The plan was that when the next prisoner died, the man would get into the coffin with the corpse. Later, after the coffin was buried outside the prison walls, the undertaker would dig it up to release the man. When he heard that a man had died, the prisoner put his plan into action. In the dead of night he climbed into the coffin with the corpse. He fell asleep. He awoke after the burial and lit a match. He then saw that the face of the corpse was that of the undertaker!"
    },
    "What A Shock Ii": {
        "question": "A man was searching a trunk in the attic when he found something that caused him to drop dead of fright. What did he find?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man discovered a box containing four glass eyes mounted to a board with a dedication to their previous owners. They had belonged to the four previous husbands of his wife. The men had all died after about a year of marriage. This was the first that he had heard of them. He was recently married and had a glass eye!"
    },
    "The Deadly Party": {
        "question": "A man went to a party and drank some of the punch. He then left early. Everyone else at the party who drank the punch subsequently died of poisoning. Why did the man not die?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The poison in the punch came from the ice cubes in it. When the man drank from the punch the ice had just been added and was still solid. Gradually, during the course of the evening, the ice melted contaminating the punch with the poison."
    },
    "Speechless": {
        "question": "Two men who were good friends had not seen each other for several years. One afternoon they met but they did not speak to each other. Neither was deaf or dumb and there was no prohibition on speaking in the place where they met. Why did they not speak to each other?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The two men were both divers. They met one afternoon while scuba diving on the sea bed."
    },
    "How To Hug": {
        "question": "A boy was about to go on his first date. Since he had never embraced a girl before he was anxious to learn a little about how to do it. He went to his local public library and saw a book entitled How to Hug. He took it home to read and was greatly disappointed; it gave him no useful advice at all. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "What the boy had picked up at the library was a volume of an encyclopedia. It was the section covering words beginning with H from How to Hug and that was what was printed on its cover."
    },
    "The Healthy Dairymaids": {
        "question": "In the eighteenth century a disease called smallpox was responsible for the deaths of millions of people worldwide. The man whom we can thank for defeating the scourge of smallpox is Edward Jenner, an English country doctor who lived from 1749 to 1823. He noticed that dairymaids never caught smallpox. From this observation he went on to develop a treatment to prevent smallpox and thereby became one of the world's most famous doctors. Why did dairymaids never catch smallpox?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Dairymaids caught the disease cowpox (a relatively harmless disease) from cows. This, however, gave them immunity from the related but much more dangerous disease smallpox. Jenner researched and developed the technique for inoculation with cowpox vaccine which eventually became widespread and overcame the bane of smallpox."
    },
    "Toothache": {
        "question": "A man was suffering from a toothache so he went to a dentist and had two bad teeth removed. The dentist had done a good job and the man was pleased that he was no longer in pain. Some time later, in a court case, judgment was rendered against the man and he was forced to pay damages to a third party because he had had those teeth removed. Why should that have been so? (Incidentally, the dentist was not at fault and was not involved in the court case.)",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "When the man had been very poor he had entered into a contract with a Swedish medical institute. For a certain sum of money he promised them his body after his death for medical research. He later inherited money and asked to buy back this obligation. The institute refused, so he sued them in court. Not only did he lose his case, but the judge ordered him to pay the institute compensation for having had his teeth removed without the permission of their future owners!"
    },
    "The Lake Problem": {
        "question": "There is a large irregularly shaped lake on your estate. It is of variable and unknown depth. There are no rivers or streams entering or leaving the lake. How would you find the volume of water in the lake?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "You pour into the lake a known quantity of a concentrated chemical or vegetable dye. After allowing some time for the harmless chemical to disperse, you take samples of the water in several places. The more diluted the solution the greater the volume of water in the lake. Precise analysis of the concentration of chemicals in the samples would give a good estimate of the water volume of the lake."
    },
    "The Realization": {
        "question": "A man was walking downstairs in a building when he suddenly realized that his wife had just died. How?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man had just visited his wife in a hospital. She was on a life-support machine following a car accident. As he was walking down the stairs all the lights went out. There had been a power cut and the emergency back-up systems had failed. He knew immediately that his wife had died."
    },
    "The Deadly Dish": {
        "question": "Two men went into a restaurant. They both ordered the same dish from the menu. After they tasted it one of the men immediately got up from the table, went outside of the restaurant, and shot himself. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The dish that the two men ordered was albatross, to re- mind themselves of when they had been stranded on a desert island many years earlier. When one of the men tasted it, he realized that he had never tasted albatross before. This meant that the meat he had been given to eat on the island was not albatross, as he had been told, but the flesh of his son who had died when they first reached the island."
    },
    "Men In Uniform": {
        "question": "Two men are in the back of a van which is parked on a country road. Both men are in uniform. One is dead. The other is angry and frustrated. What happened? ee The correct answers are as follows: (a) Un gargon. (b) Because if they fell forward they would land in the boat! (c) No. The only way you can have a widow is to be dead. (d) You would come out near where you started. It is not possible to dig through the earth's molten core. (e) albumen (f) They are a $1 note and a $100 note. (One of them is not a $1 bill; it is the $100 bill.) (g) The letter \"o\" (or nothing). (h) There is no such thing as a mommy bull, (i) His undertaker. (j) It is very likely. The average number of arms is very slightly less than two, so anyone with two arms has more than the average, (k) Guilty but in Seine. (1) Two. One on each side, (m) All 12 of them, (n) Pigs cannot say. (o) Eleven, just as before (the tide also raises the boat). A^FM ESaw 9-0 kWbh \\\\-L DajV i-ieuis si-zi 8uijb^ H?PHJO 3*\u00b0:>S :A\\opq ajEJ noX A\\oq aas uaqj, sjaMsuB pajjoD jo jaquinu jnoX dn \\e\\o\\, sjdMSuy jsax A1TVM paauPApv aqx",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The angry man was a convicted prisoner. He was being transported in the van and was handcuffed to a prison officer. When a suitable opportunity arose, the prisoner had produced a gun and demanded that the officer release him. The officer had put the key to the handcuffs in his mouth before struggling with the prisoner. The gun went off killing the officer but not before he had swallowed the key. The prisoner was therefore handcuffed to the body of the man he had just killed."
    },
    "Healthy People I": {
        "question": "In the early twentieth century many healthy people were operated on for medical conditions they did not have. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The people were examined using a new technique called X-rays. Up until this time medical understanding of the human body was based largely on the dissection of corpses. This was always done on bodies lying horizontally. X-ray examinations were performed on people who were standing up. The difference caused many internal organs to have a different shape or position. Doctors misread this different appearance under X-ray to diagnose and treat problems which did not exist. They did not think laterally!"
    },
    "Healthy People Ii": {
        "question": "A hospital director recently confirmed that many of the people admitted to his hospital were not ill at all. They were perfectly healthy, yet they were given hospital care and treatment. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The hospital was a maternity hospital and all those admitted were pregnant women."
    },
    "The Grand Prix": {
        "question": "A world-famous racing driver was approaching a bend in a formula-one Grand Prix race. Suddenly he braked very sharply and came around the bend to find crashed cars strewn dangerously across the track. He had not been able to see over or around the bend. The officials had not warned him and there was no smoke, fire, smell, or noise that he could have detected. So how did he know that something was wrong in time to avoid danger?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Although the driver could not himself see around the curve, he could see the crowd in the stands ahead looking intently round the bend. He reasoned that they were not looking at him, a world-famous racing driver, because something more interesting, possibly a crash, had occurred around the curve."
    },
    "The Stranger In The Car": {
        "question": "A man and his wife were driving quickly from the suburbs into town when their car ran out of fuel. The man left his wife in the car after telling her to keep the windows closed and the doors locked. When he returned, although the doors and windows were still locked and had remained so throughout, he found his wife dead inside and a stranger in the car. The car had not been broken into or damaged in any way, and it had no sun-roof or hatchback; the only means of entry were the doors. How had the wife died and who was the stranger?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The woman had died in childbirth. The stranger was the man's newborn son."
    },
    "Eggshell Finish": {
        "question": "Why was the man painting his portrait on an eggshell?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man was a professional clown. Each clown tries to have a unique face and copyrights his clown face by painting it on an eggshell which is then deposited with the international clown's club."
    },
    "A Fishy Tale": {
        "question": "A woman had a pet goldfish which she loved very dearly. One day she noticed that it was swimming feebly in its bowl and it looked very unwell. She rushed to the vet with her prized pet and he told her to come back in an hour. When she returned she found the goldfish swimming strongly and looking healthy again. How had the vet managed this?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The vet could see that the goldfish was dying of old age so to spare the old lady's feelings he dashed out and bought a young but identical fish and disposed of the old one."
    },
    "The Lost Passenger": {
        "question": "Little Billy was four years old and both his parents were dead. His guardian put him on a train to send him to a new home in the country. Billy could neither read nor write nor remember the address, so a large label on a string was secured around his neck clearly indicating Billy's name and destination. However, despite the best efforts and kindness of the railway staff, Billy never arrived at his new home. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Little Billy, as his name suggests, was a goat who unfortunately ate his label, so no one knew where he was supposed to go!"
    },
    "The Book": {
        "question": "A woman walked up to a man behind a counter and handed him a book. He looked at it and said, \"That will be four dollars.\" She paid the man and then walked out without the book. He saw her leave without it but did not call her back. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "She was returning an overdue library book."
    },
    "A Hairy Problem": {
        "question": "Why is it that, in general, the hair on a man's head goes grey before the hair in his moustache does?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The hair on a man's head is usually at least twenty years older than the hair in his moustache. (This solution is not guaranteed to be biologically correct but it does have an inherent plausibility.)"
    },
    "The Birds": {
        "question": "Two naturalists were walking in the country. They were both keen to protect the environment and to conserve nature and wildlife. One said to the other, \"I was impressed by the way that you hit that bird.\" The second replied, \"Yes, it was good, but not as good as that large bird that you hit earlier.\" What were they talking about?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "They were two golfers. In golf parlance, one had hit a \"birdie\" (one under par) and the other an \"eagle\" (two under par)."
    },
    "Blinded At Teatime": {
        "question": "A man was drinking a cup of tea when he was suddenly blinded. How?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "He had left his teaspoon in his cup of tea. When he raised the cup to drink, the teaspoon handle poked him in the eye, temporarily blinding him."
    },
    "Countdown": {
        "question": "A man was slowly counting but unfortunately he miscounted. A little later he suffered a sharp pain in his back. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man was counting the pins as he removed them from a new shirt. Unfortunately, he missed one."
    },
    "Weather Forecast": {
        "question": "John was watching television. Just after the midnight news there was a weather forecast: \"It is raining now and will rain for the next two days. However, in 72 hours it will be bright and sunny.\" \"Wrong again,\" snorted John. He was correct but how did he know?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "In 72 hours it would be midnight again, so it could not be \"bright and sunny.\""
    },
    "No West": {
        "question": "Let us agree that at the North Pole it is impossible to look north and at the South Pole it is impossible to look south. Then, where in the world would you be if you could look north and south but could not look east or west?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "At the exact center of the earth it is impossible to look east or west but you could look north or south."
    },
    "The Blind Beggar": {
        "question": "A blind beggar had a brother who died. What relation was the blind beggar to the brother who died? (\"Brother\" is not the answer.)",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The blind beggar was the sister of her brother who died."
    },
    "The Truck Driver": {
        "question": "A police officer saw a truck driver clearly going the wrong way down a one-way street, but did not try to stop him. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The truck driver was walking."
    },
    "Mountains Ahead": {
        "question": "You are seated next to the pilot of a small plane at an altitude of one mile. Huge mountains loom directly ahead. The pilot does not change speed, direction, or elevation, yet you survive. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The plane is sitting on the ground at the airport in Denver, Colorado."
    },
    "A Strange Christening": {
        "question": "During a christening ceremony, the godmother of the child suddenly tackled the priest who was conducting the ceremony, knocked him down, and rolled him over on the ground. Why did she do this?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The priest's surplice had caught fire from one of the candles."
    },
    "Pond Problem": {
        "question": "A man wishes to reach the island in the middle of an ornamental lake without getting wet. The island is 20 feet from each edge of the pond (see diagram) and he has two planks each 19 feet long. How does he get across?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "He lays the planks as shown in this diagram."
    },
    "Walking And Running": {
        "question": "There were two keen sportsmen. One evening at 6 p.m. one started walking at 4 miles per hour and the other started cycling at 12 miles per hour. After an hour each of them stopped. They then each ran for fifteen minutes at 8 miles per hour. They both started from the same place, A. They both kept heading in the same direction throughout and never changed course or rested during the entire 45 minutes. They both arrived at point B at the same time. How could this be and how far was it from A to B?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The two keen sportsmen started at their fitness club, one on the cycling machine and the other on the walking machine. After half an hour of indoor exercise they went for a run. The distance from A to B is 2 miles."
    },
    "Church Bells I": {
        "question": "A detective was lying in bed one Sunday morning listening to the local church bells ringing. Suddenly he realized that he was listening to a recording. How did he know?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The final chime ended abruptly and without the reverberation of the other chimes."
    },
    "Church Bells Ii": {
        "question": "One night the vicar noticed that the old clock in the church tower struck 13 times at midnight. It did the same thing the following night so he had the mechanism investigated. It was found to be in perfect order, yet the clock struck 13 again that night. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "There was a joker living in a nearby house. Each night, using his rifle and a silencer, he fired a bullet at the bell after the twelfth stroke."
    },
    "A Popular Book": {
        "question": "When this book first came out it was read only by a handful of very rich people. Now almost everyone has a copy and reads it frequently. But you cannot buy it in a bookstore or borrow it from a library. What is it?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The book is a telephone directory."
    },
    "River Problem I": {
        "question": "A man came to a river carrying a fox, a duck, and a bag of corn. There was a boat in which he could ferry one of the three items across the river at any one time. He could not leave the fox alone with the duck, nor the duck alone with the corn, so how did he get all three across? Km LOAD DAT: i nvam/IDvck OR ilftAH/lfrX oft",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "First the man took the duck across, then he came back and took the fox over. He left the fox on the far side of the river and returned with the duck. He then left the duck on the near side and took the corn over. Then he returned and took the duck across. Pretty straightforward, eh?"
    },
    "River Problem Ii": {
        "question": "This time the man reached the river with a fox, a duck, and a bag of corn, but this fox ate corn as well as ducks! There was the same boat as before in which he could take only one of the three with him. He could not leave the fox with either the corn or the duck, and, of course, the duck would gladly eat the corn if they were left together. How did he get all three across?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The man tied the duck to the back of the boat with a rope. The duck swam along behind the boat as the man ferried the fox and corn over in turn."
    },
    "River Problem Iii": {
        "question": "A man wishes to cross a wide, deep river, as shown in the diagram. There is no bridge, no boat, and he cannot swim. How does he get across?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "He stretches a long rope from point A to point B as shown."
    },
    "Bill And Ben": {
        "question": "Bill and Ben are identical twins. They are physically very alike, fit and healthy. They are both good runners and always run at the same speed. Each runs against the clock on the same track under the same conditions. Yet Ben takes ten times longer to finish than Bill. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "Bill and Ben are laboratory rats. Bill has run through a certain maze many times and has learned to complete it quickly. When Ben is introduced to the course for the first time, it takes him ten times as long."
    },
    "The Missing Brick": {
        "question": "Note: This puzzle and the one that follows it are products of the same cruel and devious mind. A young couple were inspecting a house they were considering buying. In the middle of the kitchen floor they found a single brick. The real estate agent did not know why it was there, nor did the builder, so they sent for the architect. He took the brick outside and threw it up into the air, whereupon the brick vanished from sight. What was happening?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "A duck grabbed the brick in its mouth and flew off with it!"
    },
    "A Strange Flight": {
        "question": "A small plane was flying from Albany to New York some years ago. Seated beside each other were a grumpy old man smoking a foul pipe and a grumpy old lady with a noisy pet duck on her lap. Each spent most of the journey complaining about the other. Finally a compromise was reached. The old man agreed to throw his pipe out of the window if the old lady would throw her duck out. This was done. Just as the plane was about to land, the lady was pleased to see the duck flying alongside the plane. What did the duck have in its mouth?",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answer": "The duck had a brick in its mouth (see previous puzzle)! This and the puzzle before it are reciprocal puzzles\u2014each holds the solution to the other."
    },
    "Stamp Collection": {
        "question": "A keen stamp collector who specialized in U.S. stamps saw an advertisement offering a complete set of early U.S. stamps for a fraction of what it was worth. He quickly bought it. Although it was a genuine, splendid collection and a real bargain, he was angry, not pleased. What was going on?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The man had recently left his wife to live with his mistress. The angry wife had advertised the man's prized stamp collection for sale, so he quickly bought his own stamps to stop anyone else doing so."
    },
    "Sheepish Behavior": {
        "question": "On a cold winter's day, drivers found that sheep from the fields nearby kept coming onto the road. There was no snow and the road was not warmer than the fields but whenever the sheep were ushered back to the fields they quickly returned to the road. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The sheep kept coming to the road because they liked to eat the salt put on the road to stop it freezing."
    },
    "The Tennis Match": {
        "question": "Pete challenged Jim to a tennis match for a large bet. Jim won the first set easily (6-1). Pete then offered to raise the stakes to ten times the amount. Jim readily agreed but lost the next two sets to Pete 6-1, 6-1. Pete tried hard throughout the match and never threw away a point. How did he manage to suddenly beat Jim easily?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Pete could play tennis with either hand but he was better as a left-hander. He started off playing right-handed but switched after the first set."
    },
    "Surrounded": {
        "question": "A man was on the run from the police. He was relaxing, watching a play in a crowded theatre. Suddenly he noticed that detectives were closing in on him from all directions and were covering all exits. How did he escape?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The fugitive leapt up and shouted, \"Fire, fire!\" Pandemonium broke out and the audience all rushed for the exits. He easily escaped in the confusion."
    },
    "The Banker": {
        "question": "Bernard was the president of a major Wall Street bank. One morning when he got on a crowded train he was extremely worried. When the train stopped and he alighted, he felt very sick but he was not worried anymore. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The train was a roller-coaster. The banker had promised to take his nephew for a ride but hated the experience. He was relieved it was over."
    },
    "A Curious Place": {
        "question": "If you liked this place you would rather stay for a day than a year, but if you hated it you would rather stay for a year than a day. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The place is Venus, where a day is longer than a year. Venus takes 225 Earth days to go around the sun but it takes 243 Earth days to rotate on its axis. In any event, it is unlikely that many people would like to go there for either period; the average temperature is around 885\u00b0F (460\u00b0C), the pressure is about 94 atmospheres, and there are thick clouds of sulphuric acid!"
    },
    "Grandmother's Letter": {
        "question": "A boy at boarding school ran short of money so he wrote to his grandmother asking for a small contribution. The response was a letter containing a lecture on the evils of extravagance but no money of any kind. Nevertheless, the boy was very pleased. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The boy's grandmother was Queen Victoria. In this true incident the boy sold the letter for five pounds sterling (over $20 in those days)."
    },
    "Theft At The Wedding": {
        "question": "During a wedding reception the father of the bride found that his wallet was missing. How did he find out who had taken it?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Two weeks later, when the couple returned from their honeymoon, the whole family sat down to watch the video of the wedding. They were horrified to see, caught on the camera, the groom going through his father-in-law's pockets and stealing his wallet."
    },
    "The Free Extension": {
        "question": "A man went to a builder with plans for an extension to his house. They had never met before but the builder agreed to build the extension at no charge to the man. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "It is a true story and the man was Picasso. The builder wisely decided that by building the extension he would be able to retain Picasso's rough sketch of the plans, which would be worth far more than the cost of the construction work. He was right."
    },
    "Bridge Crossing": {
        "question": "In wartime, an army had to cross a wide river. There were no boats and only one bridge, which was very narrow. Crossing the bridge would have made them sitting ducks for enemy gunfire. How did the entire army cross the river in relative safety?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "They spread out and waded across the river, which was only six inches deep."
    },
    "The Seven-year Itch": {
        "question": "While digging a garden, a woman unearthed a large metal box filled with money and jewelry. For seven years she spent none of the money and told no one what she had found. Then she suddenly bought a new house, a new car, and a fur coat. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The woman had been shipwrecked. She found a pirate's treasure but was not rescued for seven years."
    },
    "Hit Out": {
        "question": "A patient on the operating table is coming round after an operation. Suddenly he jumps up and strikes the surgeon as hard as he can. Why does he do this?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The patient is a boxer. The last thing he heard was the anesthetist counting 1, 2, 3, 4, and as he comes round he automatically tries to beat the count and resume the fight against his opponent."
    },
    "A Green Wedding": {
        "question": "A clergyman was exasperated at having to sweep up vast amounts of confetti from the front of his church after every wedding. He decreed that in the future, if people insisted on throwing something at the married couple they throw something else. What did he suggest?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The cleric suggested that people throw colored birdseed."
    },
    "Sell The Truth": {
        "question": "A manufacturer states that if middle-aged people told the truth more often he would sell a great deal more of his products. What does he manufacture?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "He made the candles that go on birthday cakes."
    },
    "The Dried Peas": {
        "question": "In a sports shop there is a soccer ball containing a quantity of dried peas. Why are they there?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The dried peas are inside soccer balls for the use of blind people, to enable them to hear the ball."
    },
    "The Dog That Did Not Die": {
        "question": "A mother told her six-year-old daughter that her pet dog had been hit by a car and killed. The little girl burst into tears. Half an hour later, the mother said that the dog was quite well and that it was all a mistake. Why did she do this?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "This story reportedly concerns the youthful Shirley Temple. Her mother told her the lie that her pet dog had been killed in order to induce real sadness and tears for a movie scene which was about to be filmed."
    },
    "High Office": {
        "question": "Tom cannot read or write or tie his shoes. He has never worked a day in his life. Despite these shortcomings, Tom is given an extremely important, prestigious, and well- paid job. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Tom is an infant who is crown prince of his country. Tom's father, the king, has just died leaving a very inexperienced new head of state."
    },
    "The Follower": {
        "question": "A woman who was driving on her own pulled into a filling station and bought some gasoline. As she drove off she noticed a stranger in a car following her. She tried to shake him off by turning, accelerating, slowing down, etc. Finally she turned into a police station, but she was shocked to see him follow her in. He was not a policeman and there were no mechanical faults with her car. Why did he follow her?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "He had seen a man hide in the back of the woman's car as she paid at the gasoline station. He followed her to warn her and was pleased to see her pull into the police station."
    },
    "Money To Burn": {
        "question": "A bank messenger, carrying a bag containing one thousand $100 bills, was robbed at gunpoint by a masked man. The man took the bag home and, without looking inside, he burnt it. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The robber's mother was a widow who owed the bank $100,000. The bank had threatened to repossess her house so her son devised a plan. He forged $100,000 and she gave it to the bank messenger, who signed for it. The forgeries were good enough to fool the messenger but would never fool the bank so the son had to rob the messenger before he got back to the bank."
    },
    "Not A Kidnapper": {
        "question": "A banker was kidnapped and held tied up and blindfolded by a single kidnapper for several days. During this time he remained seated in a silent room and he never saw or heard his kidnapper. A ransom was paid and he was released. The police arrested a suspect who had a previous criminal record and had no alibi for the period of the crime. However, during questioning, the police inspector asked the suspect one thing and then released him. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The inspector noticed that the man wrote with his left hand. He asked him to tie a knot. The man was left- handed and tied a left-handed knot. The knots tied around the hands and feet of the victim were right-handed knots."
    },
    "Ruination": {
        "question": "In a factory in Buckinghamshire, England, in the nineteenth century, a bungling employee ruined an entire batch of the factory output. However, his employer was very pleased. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "The employee discovered an important new product. He left out a primary ingredient in the batch of paper he was making. He was thus responsible for accidentally producing the first blotting paper!"
    },
    "The Bet": {
        "question": "In the eighteenth century, long before the invention of the train or the motorcar, people delivered urgent messages using riders on horses. An English duke, a notorious gambler, once bet that he could have a letter delivered from one place to another 40 kilometers (about 25 miles) away in 45 minutes or less. This was much faster than a horse could travel. How did he win the bet?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "He tied the letter inside a hollowed-out cricket ball (which is about the same size as a baseball). He then had it thrown from man to man with the men standing about 60 yards (55 metres) apart along the entire way."
    },
    "Days Off": {
        "question": "A man hired seven employees to work for him. After a few weeks he noticed that only six were ever at work on any day and that on each day a different one failed to show up for work. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "All seven employees were very religious and they all had different Sabbaths. The Christian took off on Sunday, the Greek Monday, the Persian Tuesday, the Assyrian Wednesday, the Egyptian Thursday, the Arabian Muslim Friday, and the Jew Saturday."
    },
    "An Irish Puzzle": {
        "question": "Chuck was an American on holiday in Ireland. His rental car broke down while he was in a little village and he was able to pull into a garage. There he asked how he could find someone to drive him back to Dublin. The man at the garage said, \"I haven't been here long but I am sure that Milligan is your man. He lives in the big white house at the end of the village.\" Chuck went up to the house and Milligan answered the door. \"Can you drive me to Dublin?\" asked Chuck. \"No,\" answered Milligan and explained that in his old car he never drove outside the vicinity. However, as it was late he offered Chuck a room for the night. When Chuck awoke the next morning, he was shocked to see a huge golden eagle on the top of his wardrobe gazing down at him. Why did the man at the garage direct Chuck to Milligan?",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answer": "Milligan stuffed animals. The man in the garage had heard that Milligan was a famous local taxidermist and thought that he ran some kind of taxi service!"
    },
    "A Shocking Discovery": {
        "question": "A man met a beautiful woman in a bar. After a few drinks they agreed to go back to her apartment. In the morning he awoke in an alleyway having been drugged. He checked his wallet, watch and credit cards and found that none were missing. A few minutes later he discovered something which gave him a terrible shock. What was it?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "He had a pain in his back and when he felt it he found a recently stitched incision. The woman was a lure for a crooked surgeon who removed healthy human organs and sold them to rich people needing organ transplants. On examination by X-ray the man found that one of his kidneys was gone!"
    },
    "Clean Sweep": {
        "question": "A strong woman is about to start her cleaning job when she collapses in a faint. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The woman works at a teaching hospital as an orderly. It is her job to clean bodies and get them ready for student lectures. She collapses when she sees that the body awaiting her is the body of her brother, who had earlier died in an accident. She did not know that he had left his body to science."
    },
    "Death On The Boat": {
        "question": "An expert sailor was killed while sailing his boat. He had suffered a heavy blow to the head. How had it happened?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "He had been hit by a block of frozen toilet waste ejected by a passenger jet high above him. It fell into the sea leaving no trace."
    },
    "A Rum Find": {
        "question": "Two workmen were doing a major renovation job on an old English house. They could not believe their luck when they came upon a cask of excellent Jamaican rum. They indulged in a glass or two of this rum every day until finally it ran out. They then got a nasty surprise. What was it?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "When they finished the rum they broke open the cask to find a body inside. In the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, bodies were often shipped back to England from Jamaica this way. (British admiral Horatio Nelson's body was reputedly brought home to England in a barrel of rum after the battle of Trafalgar.)"
    },
    "Broken Match": {
        "question": "A man is found dead in a field. He is clutching a broken match. What happened?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "He and a number of other passengers were making a balloon trip in a desperate attempt to escape from a country. The balloon had to lose weight to stop it from crashing. He drew the short match and had to jump."
    },
    "The Cut Finger": {
        "question": "A man is peeling potatoes when he cuts his finger. He immediately puts his hand into water and leaves it there for 30 seconds. However, when he pulls his hand out the cut has entirely disappeared. How can this have happened?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "This incident took place in South America. The unfortunate man was camping by a river. When he put his hand in the river the blood attracted piranha fish, which removed his finger including the cut!"
    },
    "The Music Stopped": {
        "question": "The music stopped. She died. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "She was a circus tightrope walker. Her most daring act was to cross a high wire while blindfolded. The band played while she crossed and when the music stopped it was the signal that she had reached the end of the wire and could safely alight. Unfortunately, one day the conductor was taken ill at the last minute and the stand-in conductor, unaware of the importance of the timing, ended the music just a little too soon. She stepped off the wire to her death."
    },
    "The Dog Choker": {
        "question": "A woman came home to find her dog choking in the hall. She rushed the dog to a nearby vet and went home while he examined the dog. When she arrived home the phone was ringing. It was the vet warning her to get out of the house at once. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The vet found two human fingers in the dog's throat. They belonged to a burglar. The vet feared that the burglar was still in the house, afraid of the dog and hiding in a closet."
    },
    "The Movie": {
        "question": "Tom and Joe went to a movie. There were many other people there. During a quiet scene, Tom drew a gun. Joe screamed, \"Don't shoot!\" but Tom shot him. Tom then left. Many people saw Tom leave and they restrained him. The police arrived and quickly released Tom. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "Tom and Joe were the stars of the movie. Tom shot Joe in a sequence in the movie. When Tom left he was mobbed by fans seeking his autograph."
    },
    "The Damaged Car": {
        "question": "A man was the proud owner of a beautiful and expensive Mercedes sports car. One day he drove it to an isolated parking area and then smashed the window, scratched the doors, and ripped out the radio. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "A few minutes earlier, the man had been the driver in a fatal hit-and-run accident. He drove to the isolated area and made it look as though the car had been stolen and vandalized. He then phoned the police to report his car stolen. (This is a true incident. He was later caught and sent to prison.)"
    },
    "The Motorcyclist": {
        "question": "A man is lying severely injured in the road. He had quite deliberately stepped out from the sidewalk in front of a motorcyclist who had hit him. Why had the man done this?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man was an examiner testing a motorcyclist. He instructed the motorcyclist to go round the block and then to do an emergency stop when the examiner stepped out from the sidewalk. Unfortunately, another motorcyclist of similar appearance came by first. Knowing nothing of the arrangement, he hit the examiner."
    },
    "Swimmer In The Forest": {
        "question": "Deep in the forest, a forest ranger found the body of man dressed only in swimming trunks, snorkel, and facemask. The nearest lake was 8 miles away and the sea was 100 miles away. How did he die?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "During a forest fire some months earlier, a fire-fighting plane had scooped up water from the lake to drop on the fire. The plane had accidentally picked up the unfortunate swimmer."
    },
    "The Dark Room": {
        "question": "A man walked into a small, dark room in a large building. After a few minutes he emerged from the dark room and left the building. A man then walked up to him and shot him dead. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man was a secret service agent who had recently killed several enemy agents. He entered a confessional in a church and confessed to the killings. However, he was under suspicion and had been followed. The man he confessed to was not a priest but an enemy agent who had seen him enter the church."
    },
    "The Two Vans": {
        "question": "In a bizarre accident, two identical vans simultaneously plunged over a dockside and into thirty feet of water. They both landed upright. Each van had a driver who was fit, uninjured by the fall, and conscious. One drowned but the other easily escaped. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "One man tried to open the front door of his van but could not because of the water pressure. The other man climbed into the back of the van, easily opened the sliding door, and thereby escaped."
    },
    "Suicide": {
        "question": "A man wakes up in a dark room. He switches on the light. A few minutes later he shoots himself. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man is a lighthouse-keeper. He woke up in the darkness with a nagging feeling that he had forgotten something. He turned on the radio and heard a report that a ship had crashed onto rocks with great loss of life. He realized that it happened because he forgot to start the light that night."
    },
    "The Plane Crash": {
        "question": "Susan watched as her husband boarded the 8:15 p.m. Air Canada flight from Toronto to Chicago. She then drove home from the airport and proceeded to watch a movie. About one hour into the movie there was a news flash; the 8:15 p.m. Air Canada flight from Toronto to Chicago had crashed with no survivors. Susan did not react. She just continued to watch the movie. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The movie had been shown a week earlier. Susan had taped it then on her videocassette recorder to watch that evening."
    },
    "One Beautiful Morning": {
        "question": "A man woke up on a beautiful summer morning. He went to the window, looked out in horror, and then shot himself. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The man was the leader of a religious cult. Believing that the world would end that night he had offered his followers the choice of taking poison or seeing the destruction of the world. Many, including his own children, had chosen poison. He and others had gone to sleep expecting to wake to Armageddon. When the next day dawned as a beautiful summer morning he knew that he had made a terrible mistake."
    },
    "The Blanket Mystery": {
        "question": "A man walked up a hill carrying a blanket. Because of this, one hundred people died. How?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "He was an Indian brave who sent smoke signals alerting a war party to the approach of a cavalry troop."
    },
    "The Deadly Bite": {
        "question": "A woman gave a man something to eat. It caused him to die. It was not poisoned or poisonous. Why did he die?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "The woman was Eve, who gave Adam the forbidden fruit from the tree in the Garden of Eden. By breaking God's instruction, Adam became mortal and died."
    },
    "The Bad Boy": {
        "question": "A man sitting at home was killed by a little boy who was outside. How?",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answer": "Out of mischief, the boy climbed onto the roof of the man's house and placed a plank of wood over the chimney. The man, who had been asleep in his parlor, was suffocated by fumes from his fire."
    },
    "The Nursery Rhyme": {
        "question": "A man is visiting a young couple who have a one-year-old daughter. He takes the baby on his knee and, with the parents present, begins to recite a nursery rhyme with the child. Within a few moments, however, he is cringing with embarrassment. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man recites the nursery rhyme \"This little piggy went to market, this little piggy stayed home ...\" while wiggling each of the baby's toes. But there is one toe too many! To his embarrassment, he finds that the baby has six toes on one foot."
    },
    "The Elder Twin": {
        "question": "One day, Kerry celebrated her birthday. Two days later, her older twin brother, Terry, celebrated his birthday. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "At the time she went into labor, the twins' mother was travelling from Guam to Hawaii. The older twin, Terry, was born on March 1st. Shortly afterwards, the mother crossed the International Date Line and Kerry, the younger twin, was born. The date was February 28th. In leap years, the younger twin celebrates her birthday two days before the older twin, since February 28 is two days before March 1st."
    },
    "Fair Shares": {
        "question": "To divide a cake equally between two people you let one cut and the other choose. How could you divide a cake among three or more people fairly? No protractors, rulers, or measuring devices are involved, just a knife.",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Suppose there are a number of people. Pick one person, A, by lot if necessary. Ask A to cut a piece of the cake that he would be happy with as his share. Now go round the group. If B objects then ask B to cut a bit off A's piece so that he (B) would be happy to take what remains. If B does not object ask C and so on. If nobody objects, then let A have that piece. Continuing this process will give a division which satisfies everybody."
    },
    "The Sealed Envelope": {
        "question": "One morning a jealous wife found in the mail a letter addressed to her husband. How did she remove the letter from the sealed envelope without breaking the seal or tearing the envelope and then put it back in the envelope so that her husband did not know that the letter had been read?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "There is usually a small gap at the top of the envelope where the flap has been folded over. The wife inserted a knitting needle through the gap and under the fold of the letter. By rotating the needle she wound the letter tightly around it. She then removed it, read the letter, and replaced it using the actions in reverse."
    },
    "Tattoo": {
        "question": "Why did a significant number of people have a Crucifixion scene tattooed on their bodies? These people did not share any particular religious beliefs.",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The men were sailors, who were often flogged for minor offenses on board ship. Some captains refused to whip a man's back if it carried the image of Christ."
    },
    "Suitcase For Hire": {
        "question": "Pat went into a luggage shop to buy a suitcase. The assistant said, \"It is most unusual to buy a suitcase. Why don't you rent one like all our other customers?\" Why should this be so?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Pat was a Westerner in Tokyo. Houses there are small and, in order to save space, people tend to rent any large item which they might use only occasionally. Most Japanese rent the suitcases they take on holiday."
    },
    "The Tennis Tournament": {
        "question": "A total of 213 people enter a knockout tennis tournament. What is the least number of matches that must be played to decide an overall winner?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The answer is 212 matches including the final. There is a very easy way to solve this seemingly difficult problem. Each match must produce one winner and one loser. Everyone except the tournament winner loses exactly once, so the number of matches is exactly the same as the number of losers. So to have 212 losers there must be exactly 212 matches."
    },
    "The Key": {
        "question": "Every night before he went to bed, a man carefully locked all the doors of his house. Then he placed the front-door key inside a bucket of cold water. In the morning he retrieved the key from the bucket in order to open the door. Why did he do this?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man's wife was an habitual sleepwalker. She had previously opened the front door in her sleep and walked out into the road. He placed the key in the bucket of cold water so that, if she reached into the water to get it, the cold sensation would waken her."
    },
    "That's Fast!": {
        "question": "While Harry was working in his garage he made something travel at over 3000 miles (4800 kilometers) per hour. What on earth was it?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Harry broke a pane of glass. A crack in glass starts in one place and travels across the glass at a speed of over 3000 miles (4800 kilometres) per hour."
    },
    "A Man In A Bar": {
        "question": "A man walked into a bar and asked for a certain drink. The bartender apologized that he had run out of that particular drink but he offered the man any other drink in the house free. The man refused and walked out. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man was a priest conducting a communion service in a nearby church when they ran short of altar wine. Only red wine would do."
    },
    "The 88 Hours": {
        "question": "A man sat perfectly still for 88 hours. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man had a nasty toothache and he went to the dentist at 5 p.m. on a Friday evening. The dentist's assistants, including the anesthetist, had all gone and the dentist could not administer an anesthetic. The man insisted that the dentist should operate even without anesthetic so the dentist said that he would have to strap the man into the chair. This was done. The dentist then suffered a heart attack and died. The poor man was left strapped in the chair and unable to move. It was a holiday weekend and no staff reported for work until 9 a.m. on the following Tuesday morning\u201488 hours later."
    },
    "Sand Trap": {
        "question": "Why did a man go to great trouble to bury in the desert fifteen brand-new Mercedes-Benz cars, all greased and wrapped in plastic?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "This incident reputedly occurred during the war between Israel and Egypt. Because of import duties, Mercedes cars were much more expensive in Egypt than in Israel. When Israel seized vast tracts of the Sinai desert, a clever Israeli businessman realized that the land would have to be handed back to Egypt after the war. By burying the cars he effectively exported them when the border shifted without them actually moving! His Egyptian associate subsequently sold them at a handsome profit."
    },
    "Building Demolition": {
        "question": "In Australia a perfectly good building was demolished and an almost identical one erected on exactly the same site. The original building was in good condition, it had no defects and there was no issue of safety or planning permission. Why was it demolished?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The building was the Australian National Mint. Over many years, so much gold dust had been absorbed into the fabric of the building that it was well worthwhile to demolish the building, extract the gold, and rebuild."
    },
    "The Torn Cheque": {
        "question": "A man writes a cheque, signs it, and then tears it into exactly 217 pieces. He then puts it in the mail. Can you give a rational explanation for his behavior?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man had ordered a bicycle for his son as a gift. The advertisement had not stated that it came in 217 pieces as a self-assembly kit. This was his revenge."
    },
    "The Weather Report": {
        "question": "A terse weather report once stated that the temperature in a certain place at midnight on June 1st was a certain number of degrees. Where was the place?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "Since the weather report did not specify degrees in Fahrenheit or Celsius/centigrade, the temperature must have been the same in both scales. Only a temperature of -40 degrees is the same in both Fahrenheit and Celsius/ centigrade. That temperature for June would certainly make the place Antarctica."
    },
    "Odd Animals": {
        "question": "What do these animals have in common: koala bear, prairie dog, firefly, silkworm, jackrabbit, guinea pig?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "They are all impostors: The koala bear is not a bear; it is a marsupial. The prairie dog is not a dog; it is a rodent. The firefly is not a fly; it is a beetle. The silkworm is not a worm; it is a caterpillar. The jackrabbit is not a rabbit; it is a hare. The guinea pig is not a pig; it is a rodent (and it is not from Guinea, but from South America)."
    },
    "The Shorter Program": {
        "question": "A music program on a well-respected radio station finished exactly eight minutes earlier than it was scheduled to. An embarrassed official gave the explanation for this mistake. What was it? How long was the program supposed to last? (It is possible to work this out.)",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "It was a program of contemporary classical music played from a record. The record was played at the wrong speed\u201445 rpm instead of 33 rpm. Because of the esoteric nature of the composition, this mistake was not noticed until the end of the transmission. It can easily be calculated that the program should have lasted thirty minutes."
    },
    "Traffic Trouble": {
        "question": "How did a change in state traffic regulations lead to an increase in trade for local sex shops? (The answer is not obscene!)",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "A new traffic regulation, designed to encourage car sharing, stated that only cars carrying two or more passengers could use certain lanes of the freeway. This led to motorists buying blow-up dolls to give the appearance that they were carrying passengers!"
    },
    "Blackmail": {
        "question": "A rather nasty criminal developed a seemingly foolproof way of extracting money from bereaved families. He would scan the obituary columns in order to choose the name of a wealthy man who had recently died. Then he sent an invoice for pornographic books addressed to the man and claiming payment for goods previously despatched. To avoid any scandal the family would invariably pay. How was he eventually caught out?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The criminal sent an invoice to a blind man who had recently died. His widow immediately knew that it must be a scam."
    },
    "A Good Night's Sleep": {
        "question": "A man in a hotel was unable to sleep. He got up, opened the window drapes, went back to bed and fell asleep easily. How come?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man was deaf. He had to get up early for an important meeting and he was so worried about oversleeping that he could not get to sleep. After opening the curtains, however, he knew that the sunlight would wake him up, so he was no longer worried and fell asleep easily."
    },
    "Grateful For Poor Service": {
        "question": "A man saw something advertised at a certain price and went to buy it. An official refused to sell it to him even though the man could pay and other men and women were sold it. Later the man was very glad that his purchase had been refused. Why was he refused and why was he glad?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The man wanted to buy a first-class ticket on the maiden voyage of the luxury liner Titanic in 1912. He was refused because he was black. The Titanic sank with great loss of life."
    },
    "Free T-shirts": {
        "question": "A man was watching television when he saw an advertisement offering free T-shirts to the first 100 viewers who phoned in. He called the number given, stated his size, and received his free T-shirt in a few days. Later he very much regretted doing this. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "This is a true story from Connecticut. The advertisement was a trap for people who used illegal devices to tap into cable television circuits without paying. It was placed by the owners of the cable television network and could be seen only by people using illegal decoders.The \"free\" T-shirt was soon followed by a letter informing them that they were committing a federal crime and imposing a $2000 fine. The recipients had little choice but to pay up."
    },
    "Bank Robbery I": {
        "question": "A gang robbed a bank. They tied up the staff and then hurriedly left the bank. One of the bank staff struggled free and did something which quickly led to the apprehension of the gang. What was it?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The bank was on the sixth floor of a tall building. The staff member who struggled free pressed a security button which froze all the elevators. The gang was trapped inside the elevator until the police came to arrest them."
    },
    "Bank Robbery Ii": {
        "question": "A gang stole a bank security van containing over $700,000. Their plan was executed perfectly and they got clean away. The police had no trace of them and the gang were free to divide and spend the loot. However, they were extremely frustrated. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "The robbers discovered to their horror that the currency consisted only of freshly minted coins. All shops and banks were alerted to watch out for anyone trying to exchange large amounts of coin, so the gang was reduced to playing slot machines!"
    },
    "A Puzzling Attack": {
        "question": "Four rational and reasonable people were seated around a table. Suddenly three of them jumped up and viciously beat the fourth one senseless. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Very Hard",
        "answer": "They had been trying to solve a lateral thinking problem\u2014 this one in fact. When the one posing the problem revealed the answer the others beat him up. (In setting this puzzle, always describe the group and the problem poser in terms of the number of men and women in your own group.)"
    },
    "A Fire Escape": {
        "question": "Nicole awakes to the smell of smoke. Although she realizes the danger in her situation, she makes no attempt to leave the building where she has been sleeping. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Nicole was locked in a jail cell and realized it was futile for her to attempt to leave until the guard unlocked her cell door."
    },
    "The Unsuccessful Suicide": {
        "question": "Feeling suicidal, a man tries to kill himself by jumping off a high-rise building. He miraculously survives the fall. Why don't the police charge him with attempted suicide?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The building was on fire at the same time the man tried to commit suicide, leading the police to believe he was only trying to save himself from the fire."
    },
    "Theft In A Pub": {
        "question": "J.P. visits his favorite local pub. While coming back from the restroom he sees a stranger take his wallet from his jacket, which he had left draped over his chair. J.P. watches the thief spend the money. Can you explain this passive response?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "J. P. was a counterfeiter. He left the wallet in plain view, knowing it was likely to be stolen, and the money spent. He then watched the transaction, thereby learning if the bogus money would pass as real currency without having to take the risk himself."
    },
    "To Tell A Mockingbird": {
        "question": "Christopher learns about a terrible crime that has been committed by John and Bob. He has known both of these men for many years and cares for them equally. Why, then, does he only report John to the authorities and not Bob?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Christopher was a priest. In the confessional at church, John told the priest about his involvement in the crime. Christopher later learned of Bob's role while attending a church bake sale. Catholic priests are constrained from revealing information imparted to them in a confessional."
    },
    "More Than He Bargained For": {
        "question": "One day, while he is window shopping, Bert is suddenly aware that his retirement nest egg is gone. Can you explain how Bert came to this realization?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "While window shopping, Bert watched a news story about the grand opening of a new shopping center. Bert immediately recognized the site as the location where he had buried his accumulated wealth."
    },
    "The Frustrated Futures Trader": {
        "question": "Every day, on his drive to work in downtown Manhattan from his home in New Jersey, Joe is frustrated by his lack of foresight. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Over the weekend, Joe traded in his car for a vintage Jaguar which had its steering wheel on the right-hand side. The following Monday, he realized he would have to get out of his car every day on his way to work in order to pay the toll at the George Washington Bridge."
    },
    "An Untimely Death": {
        "question": "Cal loves his pet, Roscoe, very much. In fact, he even brings Roscoe to work with him every day. After returning from lunch one day, Cal and his co-workers were very alarmed to find Roscoe dead. Can you explain the panic which followed their discovery?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Cal was a coal miner and his pet, Roscoe, was a canary. In a bygone era, canaries were sometimes used to alert miners to the presence of flammable gases accumulating in the mines, which could cause a disastrous explosion. The small birds' low tolerance for gases would cause them to die, thereby warning the miners of the danger."
    },
    "The Long Road Ahead": {
        "question": "Bubba sets out on a hazardous journey. Although his destination is in sight the entire time, he has to travel 400 miles in order to reach his destination. Can you explain the circumstances surrounding this event?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Bubba was a race car driver. Therefore he could see his destination, the finish line, at any moment during the race."
    },
    "The Prison Break": {
        "question": "Jim develops an elaborate plan to escape from prison. After successfully escaping, Jim makes a mocking phone call to the prison authorities. He reveals that he is only a few miles away at a local tavern frequented by many off-duty prison guards. The authorities are dismayed by this news, yet make no attempt to take him back into custody. Can you explain their unusual reaction?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Jim was hired by the state authorities to test the security system at a new prison. He posed as a prisoner in order to attempt an escape. When he succeeded, the authorities were embarrassed by his accomplishment."
    },
    "Wood That I Could": {
        "question": "Tom is stranded on a island. Although he has firewood and matches, he spends several nights shivering and cold. On the tenth night it begins to rain and Tom decides to light a fire. What's going on here?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Tom was expecting a boat to pass by the island on the tenth night. Since he had only enough wood for one fire, Tom waited until the boat was in sight. Coincidentally, this was the same night that it began to rain."
    },
    "A Shooting At Midnight": {
        "question": "A man walks into his backyard in the middle of the night and fires a gun. Due to his strange behavior he never sees another sunrise. (No, he didn't kill himself.) Can you explain this odd occurrence?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man shot his rooster, which had awakened him with its crowing every morning for the past ten years. Since he had recently retired, there was no longer any reason to be awakened at such an early hour."
    },
    "Execution At Dawn": {
        "question": "After a short court-martial, General Gordo selects seven of his best marksmen to serve on a firing squad. They fire on the condemned man at point-blank range, yet only six bullets are found in his body. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "When firing squads were used to carry out death sentences, a blank round was loaded into one of the guns used by the firing squad. This would allow each member of the firing squad to believe that he had not caused the prisoner's death."
    },
    "The Leaky Boat": {
        "question": "Al is a well-known boat builder. He spends nearly a year hand-crafting a boat from the finest timber available. When he finally launches his boat it sinks within a few minutes. Satisfied, he returns home. Can you explain the man's reaction?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Al intentionally sank the boat knowing this would cause the wood to swell. This would seal the cracks in the hull."
    },
    "Wonder Woman": {
        "question": "A woman is at work. She is asked to move a two-ton piece of equipment. Although no one assists her and there are no mechanical aids available, she easily completes the task. How does she comply with this seemingly impossible request?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The woman was an astronaut aboard the Space Shuttle. In zero gravity conditions, large heavy objects can be easily manipulated."
    },
    "By The Time I Get To Phoenix": {
        "question": "One day Nick boasted to his friend, Frank, that he had once driven an automobile from coast to coast in less than twenty-four hours. Naturally, Frank realizes that Nick has finally stretched the truth to the breaking point. Frank offers his boastful buddy five thousand dollars if Nick can duplicate his miraculous driving feat. Although it pained him greatly to do so, Frank conceded defeat as soon as Nick explained how it could be done. What was Nick's explanation?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Nick knew that Frank would assume that he was referring to the West and East Coasts of America; however, he was thinking of a trip from the Adantic Coast to the Gulf Coast of Florida. In fact, his trip took far less than the 24 hours he boasted about."
    },
    "Dead Men Tell No Tales": {
        "question": "A search party was looking for a man. They finally found him lying in a field covered in blood. Later that day, the coroner revealed that the man had been shot twice. Without any other physical evidence, the police quickly arrested the murderer. How were the police able to ascertain the identity of the criminal?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was still alive when the search party found him. He was able to tell the police the identity of his attacker. He later died at the hospital."
    },
    "Out Of Bounds": {
        "question": "In November of 1952 a momentous football game took place between two fierce rivals. With two minutes to go in the fourth quarter, a field goal was kicked to tie the score at 13\u201413. Despite the loud protests of the players and spectators, the game was declared a draw, and it was not completed or replayed. Why would the game officials make such a dissatisfying and unpopular ruling?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The game was taking place in Cuba at the Guantanamo Bay Naval base. The ball was kicked over a fence into Cuban territory, making it dangerous to retrieve."
    },
    "Swimming With The Fishes": {
        "question": "A man was fishing on a large lake when he suddenly fell in. Although the man was an accomplished swimmer and was only a few yards away from shore, he eventually drowned. Why did this happen?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was ice fishing on a frozen lake. Unable to find the hole through which he had fallen, he consequently drowned."
    },
    "The Domino Effect": {
        "question": "Charlotte picks up a teaspoon of sugar using only one finger. How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The sugar was in the form of a cube, allowing Charlotte to pick up it by merely wetting her fingertip and touching its top."
    },
    "The Running Man": {
        "question": "Alex is at a sporting event, minding his own business and, in fact, in deep concentration. Suddenly, right in front of him, a man appears, takes something from him, and quickly runs off. Instead of trying to catch the man and retrieve the item, Alex simply stands passively and watches as he runs away. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was a teammate who took a baton from Alex's hand during the course of a relay race."
    },
    "Shortchanged": {
        "question": "Minnie receives a sure-fire gambling tip that would put her on Easy Street. She has several dollars' worth of change in her pocket and finds a working pay phone to call her bookie. Why, then, does she lose out on her one and only chance at making the \"big score\"?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Minnie was traveling in Mexico when she received the tip. Unfortunately, all of the change she had in her pocket was still American currency. Minnie could not find anyone to exchange her money."
    },
    "Money Troubles": {
        "question": "A man is charged with a crime and placed in jail. His bond is set at one hundred thousand dollars. Although he desperately wants to leave and could easily get the money, he decides to remain in jail. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was charged with embezzling large sums of money. In order to post his bond he would have to use the money he had embezzled. This would have strengthened the case against him."
    },
    "Photo Finished": {
        "question": "Ben is accused of murder. He claimed that at the time the murder had taken place, he was on vacation in the South Pacific. To back up his alibi he provided the police with videotapes of his week-long vacation. Why, then, was he eventually convicted of the crime?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Ben had filmed his \"week-long\" vacation over the course of one day. On examining the tape, the police noticed that the phases of the moon did not change throughout the entire video. The moon would have changed significantly over a span of one week."
    },
    "Keep On Truckin'": {
        "question": "Lewis attends the International Convention of Truckers. While in the noisy convention hall he sees a group of men on the far side of the room. He does not recognize any of them. Without hearing them speak or seeing anything distinctive about their wardrobe, Lewis announces to his colleagues: \"There's the group from Australia. I think I'll go over and introduce myself.\" How did he come to his rapid and accurate conclusion? Clues: 47-48/ Answer: 84 Mr. Gray's Anatomy Mr. Gray's life was going perfectly. He was healthy, successful, and had a beautiful family. Therefore his parents were shocked when he made a very strange request. Mr. Gray asked that his head be cut off. Why did he make this bizarre request?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Being a truck driver himself, Lewis knew that after many hours behind the wheel, his left arm would become more tan than other. In Australia vehicles are driven on the left-hand side of the road. Lewis saw that the truck drivers' right arms were heavily tanned and correcdy surmised that they were from Australia."
    },
    "Potted Plants": {
        "question": "When Fred decided to grow a large quantity of marijuana on his remote farm, he thought he had the perfect plan. He would grow the plants in a large barn using artificial lights. No one ever visited him and he was the only person involved in the operation. So it was a great surprise when, months later, Fred was arrested and his illicit crop seized. Fred could not figure out what had caused his scheme to unravel. Can you?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "An alert employee at the local power company notified the authorities that Fred was using an exorbitant amount of electricity, as compared to his previous bills. The police soon suspected that this additional power was being used for illicit purposes."
    },
    "The Sky Diver": {
        "question": "Pierre went skydiving near his home in Dallas, Texas. As a result, Pierre saved his brother's life. Strangely though, his brother lived in Boston and hadn't seen or spoken to his brother Pierre for a great many years. How could this miracle have taken place?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Unfortunately for Pierre, he did not survive the jump. However, his brother was in need of a transplant and was blessed enough to receive the necessary organ from an ideal donor."
    },
    "Eyes On The Prize": {
        "question": "The Stardust Lounge was holding its annual raffle. First prize was $1,000 dollars in cash. Hopeful participants wrote their names on slips of paper which were then placed in a large bowl. When Alexander Turnbull's name was announced as the winner, he was both surprised and excited, yet he did not claim the money. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Alexander's name and credit cards were being used by an impostor ever since his wallet had been stolen. As he had not filled out a raffle ticket, when his name was announced as the winner he realized that the person impersonating him must have been present and filled one out. He simply waited around for the prize to be claimed in order to discover the identity of the culprit."
    },
    "The Alaskan Dream": {
        "question": "Scott is an expert outdoorsman, pursuing his dream by living alone in the remote Alaskan wilderness. Scott has everything he needs, and would prefer to remain a recluse, yet he will have to leave his home in four years. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Scott will need to travel to a hospital in order to have the battery replaced in his pacemaker within four years."
    },
    "A Bridge To Fear": {
        "question": "On her way to work one blustery winter day, Patty slipped and fell over the railing of the world's highest suspension bridge. She was wearing only her regular office attire, yet she was not harmed in any way. How could that be?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Patty was standing near one end of the bridge. She fell only a few feet to the ground."
    },
    "Petty Cash": {
        "question": "When Pauline's house was burglarized, five dollars were taken from a dresser drawer. Nothing else was stolen or damaged. After filing a claim with her insurance company, Pauline was paid one thousand dollars for her loss. What was the reason behind this settlement?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Pauline is an avid coin collector. The five antique silver dollars were appraised at one thousand dollars."
    },
    "Feast Or Famine": {
        "question": "After months of subsisting on a starvation diet, Paul finally obtained some decent food. Why, then, did he pass up this opportunity to enjoy a perfectly good meal?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Paul was a P.O.W. While incarcerated, his captors did not abide by the Geneva Convention rules concerning the treatment of prisoners of war. Paul refused to eat after realizing that he was being fattened up for his impending release."
    },
    "An Axe To Grind": {
        "question": "When Jerry, a lumberjack known for exaggeration, boasted of cutting down a one-hundred-year-old maple tree in ten seconds using only a small axe, his friend Mac had had enough. He challenged Jerry to prove his incredible claim. How did the brawny braggart succeed?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The tree is a Japanese bonsai variety. Two-hundred-year-old bonsai trees typically grow only a few feet in height and a few inches in diameter."
    },
    "The Root Of The Problem": {
        "question": "Mr. Finkel was an avid gardener who was very proud of his landscaping and horticultural skills. Unfortunately, Mr. Finkel's hobby caused the death of a neighbor after he planted a tree in his backyard. How could his gentle pastime have turned deadly?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mr. Finkel accidentally cut his neighbor's phone line while planting the tree. His neighbor suffered a heart attack and was unable to call for help."
    },
    "The Sky's The Limit": {
        "question": "Henry, a poor but lucky fisherman, finds a treasure map that promises great wealth-beyond his wildest dreams. He ultimately retrieves the loot which lay buried on an island barely a day's sail from his home. Why did Henry wait three months to retrieve the loot?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The treasure map relied on celestial navigation. Therefore Henry needed to wait until a specific date for a constellation to appear in the sky."
    },
    "The Discouraging Discovery": {
        "question": "During the aftermath of a violent storm, Vern is pleased to find that his house has come through unscathed. Later that day, Vern discovers that he has suffered a large loss in the value of his property. What led Vern to this unfortunate conclusion?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Vern had purchased his house for an exorbitant price with the understanding that the house had been constructed for W.C. Meadows, the famous movie star. In fact, the real estate agent had told him that W.C. Meadows had planted a sapling in the front yard when he first moved in. The storm had knocked over this very tree. While cutting up the tree, Vern counted the rings and discovered the tree was thirty years old. Unfortunately for Vern, W.C. Meadows had died forty years ago."
    },
    "The Expert Pilot": {
        "question": "A man is flying a plane. When the engine begins to stall, the pilot immediately switches to his reserve fuel tank. Later in the flight, the landing gear warning light comes on, yet the pilot is not concerned with this new, potentially lethal problem. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was a Japanese kamikaze. Since he intended to crash his plane into an American battleship, he had no reason to be concerned with the faulty landing gear."
    },
    "What's It All About?": {
        "question": "Mack goes on an eating binge for several days, which ends up costing him two million dollars. How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mack is a champion featherweight boxer. After his binge he was unable to make weight for his title bout."
    },
    "The Mysterious Motorist": {
        "question": "Every so often, Jennifer pulls off to the side of the road and opens the trunk of her car. She doesn't get anything out of the trunk or put anything into it. Can you give a reason for this seemingly strange activity?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Jennifer is a police officer. Opening the trunk partially disguises her patrol car from speeding motorists."
    },
    "A Sense Of Direction": {
        "question": "On the first day of a business trip to Japan, BJ. arrives at a large office building. She had never been there before, and could not read any of the signs. Without seeing or talking with anyone, she quickly makes her way through a labyrinth of hallways to arrive at her destination. How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "B J. was the architect who had designed the building. Knowing the layout of the building, she easily found her way to her destination."
    },
    "Moving Day": {
        "question": "Herb gets a job in a new city. On the day of his move, Herb causes a traffic jam without ever leaving his home. How does Herb create such a monumental disturbance?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Herb lives on a houseboat. While moving his houseboat, Herb causes a drawbridge to be raised, thereby blocking a major road. Mr. Gray's Anatomy Mr. Gray wants to have his head frozen once he is dead. He believes that, at some future time, technology will exist that will be able to bring the minds in frozen heads back to life."
    },
    "I Bid Thee Farewell": {
        "question": "Dee places an ad soliciting bids for the construction of a new office building. In response, she receives two bids. Without opening either, she immediately throws one away. Why did she make such a rash decision?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Dee works for a delivery service. The bid was delivered by a rival company. Taking offense to this, she discarded the bid without looking at it."
    },
    "Shed Some Light": {
        "question": "A hermit inherits a large amount of money and has a new house built. Although he enjoys his new home immensely, he only uses the lights during the day. Why does he do this?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The hermit's house was powered by photo-electric solar cells, which only operated in direct sunlight."
    },
    "A Hunting Accident": {
        "question": "Mick often went hunting in the extensive marshlands which surrounded the local airport. One day, a plane was forced to make a crash landing. Although Mick never fired his rifle, or any other weapon, his hunting trip was directly responsible for the tragedy. How did Mick's hunting trip turn deadly?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mick is a practitioner of falconry. One of his hunting falcons was sucked into the jet's intake and caused the engine to fail."
    },
    "Down On The Farm": {
        "question": "Two farmers, Jedro and Jason, have farms that are adjacent to each other. They both plant the same crop and use identical techniques. Furthermore, both of the farms measure ten miles long by ten miles wide. Why, then, is Jedro able to produce ten percent more grain than Jason every year?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Jedro's farm contained large hills, which increased its total surface area by 10%."
    },
    "Long Time No See": {
        "question": "Kathy receives a call from an old friend and roommate on the phone. She has known this person intimately for years, yet Kathy does not recognize her friend's voice. How can this be?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Both the women had taken a vow of silence while living in a convent. It was only later, after having left the convent, that they were allowed to speak"
    },
    "Whose Vault Is It?": {
        "question": "A burglar is stealing two bars of gold, each so heavy he cannot lift them above his waist. On his way out of the vault, he suddenly sees a security camera ahead. Thinking quickly, he disguises himself without putting down the gold bars. How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Using bubble gum, the thief disguised himself by blowing a large bubble, thereby concealing his face from the camera."
    },
    "On The Boardwalk": {
        "question": "Patrick has a regular delivery route along the Myrtle Beach boardwalk. Each day he makes his deliveries using a handcart and returns to his shop at the north end of the boardwalk. Although he is not physically tired, Patrick always finds that the return trip, with his now empty cart, is more difficult. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Patrick deliveries helium balloons. The helium exerts a lifting force on the cart, thereby making it more difficult to push when empty."
    },
    "The Secret Meeting": {
        "question": "A man and a woman meet at their regular time and place. They have an intimate conversation together, yet neither one can describe the other to their friends. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Their intimate conversations take place in a confessional. Therefore neither one can clearly see the other's face."
    },
    "Temporary Housing": {
        "question": "Jake builds a house, and although anyone would be satisfied with the construction, he knows he'll have to rebuild it in fifteen years. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Jake had built a large tree house, which surrounded the main trunk. When the tree grows in diameter, the framing of the tree house will gradually be destroyed."
    },
    "A Customs Conundrum": {
        "question": "Eric spends his vacation in the Swiss Alps. Unfortunately, he ends up spending the greater part of his visit in the hospital, after having taken a nasty spill while skiing. On his return trip home to the U.S., the authorities do not ask him to show his passport. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Eric eventually died as a result of his skiing accident. His body was being flown home in the cargo section of a plane."
    },
    "The Yard Sale": {
        "question": "After buying a new oven, Gerald sold his old one to a stranger. Although the stranger offered to pay cash, Gerald, nonetheless, had a very good reason for insisting that the transaction take place at a bank. Rather than be offended, the stranger clearly understood the reason for this unusual request. Why did Gerald make this demand?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Gerald is blind and fears he would be shortchanged by the purchaser. The bank teller would insure the proper amount is paid.  "
    },
    "The Master Mechanic": {
        "question": "Gary, a highly skilled auto mechanic, climbed under the chassis of Shawn's midnight-blue Pontiac GTO. Ten minutes later he climbed out from under the car. Gary did not inspect or repair the automobile, nor did he offer any professional advice to the car's owner. In fact, Shawn knew full well that Gary had never even touched the vehicle. Immediately afterwards, and as a result of what had just occurred, Shawn unhesitatingly paid Gary five hundred dollars. Why would he do this?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Gary had made a wager with Shawn that he could lie in the middle of a busy highway during rush hour for ten minutes. In order to safely win the bet, Gary drove Shawn's car to a nearby highway, feigned car trouble and climbed under the GTO. Ten minutes later he emerged five hundred dollars richer!"
    },
    "The King's Test": {
        "question": "An eccentric king wanted to find the smartest person in his kingdom. He had one bucket of milk and another bucket of water, both filled to the rim. He then said, \"Whoever can mix these together to form a 50/50 mixture without using anything other than these two buckets will receive a thousand gold coins.\" How did one man finally succeed?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The peasant left both buckets outside in freezing weather. Later that day, he took the now frozen blocks of water and milk out of the buckets, broke them into pieces and put them back into the buckets to yield an equal mixture of both."
    },
    "Hard Of Darkness": {
        "question": "Tim and Ralph were the best of friends. They were also very competitive. Over the years, Tim and Ralph have met each and every challenge, both mental and physical, posed by the other. One day, Tim succeeds in posing a challenge that Ralph cannot possibly meet. What is the challenge?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "To get a tan. For Ralph, who is an albino, this is impossible. Harry the Homeowner Harry had bought a doll house for his daughter. She had, of course, wasted no time in rearranging the furniture inside."
    },
    "Crustacean Vacation": {
        "question": "After being away on business for a week, Milton checked with his son to see how their crabbing business had prospered during his absence. When his son reported that things had slacked off all week, the father was disappointed, yet he trusted his son's response. The next day, as they prepared to launch their boat, Milton began scolding his son for lying. How did he know his son had deceived him?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "As Milton launched the small boat they used to check the crab pots, he discovered a patch of dead grass where the boat had been resting. This indicated that the boat had not been moved for quite some time."
    },
    "Attorney Client Privilege": {
        "question": "Sam is talking to his lawyer in jail. They are very upset because the judge has refused to grant bail. Oddly enough, at the end of the conversation Sam is allowed to leave the jail. Why? Clues: 61 / Answer-. 77 Harry the Homeowner Harry goes out and buys a new house. One day he re- urns home to find that all of the furniture in the house has been completely rearranged. Strangely, Harry is not in the least bit surprised or irritated, even though he didn't ask anyone to do this. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Sam is visiting his lawyer, who had been arrested and jailed."
    },
    "The Big Game": {
        "question": "One of the most prominent citizens of Chicago once offered highly prized football tickets to forty people whom he despised. Can you explain his unusual generosity?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The prominent citizen was the police chief. He called several of the city's most-wanted criminals, and claimed that they had won the tickets in a random drawing. When the criminals arrived to claim their tickets, they got more than they bargained for!"
    },
    "First Edition": {
        "question": "Mr. Jones drives a hundred miles to the nearest book store. He pays twenty dollars of his hard-earned money to purchase a first edition of a new book. After many hours of reading, he concludes that the book is poorly written, boring, and inaccurate. Rather than be upset, Mr. Jones is instead greatly pleased with his purchase. Why would this be?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mr. Jones was a well known historian, and author of several books on the subject of World War II. He and his rival, Mr. Smith, had both recently published books on the Battle of the Bulge. He knew, happily, that his book would now seem so much the better in comparison."
    },
    "A Reverting Development": {
        "question": "An artist, working in his private studio, had just finished a new creation, so he decided to take a break and visit an old friend. During his visit a violent storm erupted. The artist soon realized that his work of art would be ruined. How did he know?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The storm caused a power line to be knocked down. Since the artist had been working on an ice sculpture in his refrigerated studio, he depended upon electric power to keep the work of art from melting."
    },
    "Monumental Achievement": {
        "question": "A man makes his way to the top of a hundred-foot-high monument in the center of a small town. He then jumps off the monument without the aide of a parachute, glider, or other such device. He is not harmed in any way. How did he manage to do this?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The monument the man had jumped off of was underwater. The whole town had been flooded years earlier, when a hydroelectric dam was built for a neighboring city."
    },
    "Room Despair": {
        "question": "A man paid thousands of dollars to build an addition onto his primary residence. Yet, after the construction was completed, he never went into that part of the house again. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was confined to a wheelchair. He wanted the extra room to accommodate visiting friends and relatives. The addition consisted of a second story on top of what had been a single-level home."
    },
    "The Pilot's Puzzle": {
        "question": "A pilot was in an emergency situation, and needed to land his aircraft in unfamiliar territory. He immediately spotted two possible landing sites, the first of which was a flat and open field. The second site was inhabited by grazing livestock and had a rough terrain. Why, then, did he choose the latter?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The pilot was flying in a war zone. He had been instructed to look for grazing animals as an indication of a safe landing area. If land mines had been present, the animals would most likely have set them off as they grazed."
    },
    "An Explosive Situation": {
        "question": "While at work one day, a man hears a loud explosion and is thrown hundreds of feet through the air. This is witnessed by many people, but no one attempts to give him aid. Why didn't they help the man?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man worked for a traveling circus as a human cannonball."
    },
    "Leave It Or Not": {
        "question": "Elizabeth lives in a neighborhood known for its well- tended and manicured lawns. Yet, for some reason, while Elizabeth is busily raking up leaves from her trees, all of her neighbors are content to simply ignore theirs. Can you explain this situation?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Elizabeth had moved in a few months before. For an upcoming art show, she decided to paint a 4-pane landscape of her house year 'round. Because it was only August, and she was a novice, she felt it would help her visualize the winter scene if she removed the leaves from her ornamental trees."
    },
    "Shore Sighted": {
        "question": "A group of friends set out for a leisurely day of boating and become stranded when the motor dies. The boat has no other means of reaching shore, and isn't equipped with a radio, but the friends do find some flares. Still, although they are within sight of hundreds of people on shore, they are not rescued for several hours. Why does rescue take so long?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The stranded group set off flares in the hope that those seeing them would come to their rescue. Unfortunately, the boat trip took place on a holiday, part of the reason for the outing, and the onlookers seeing the flares assumed that they were simply part of the firework displays that were part of the holiday celebrations."
    },
    "The Perfect Crime": {
        "question": "Rocky bludgeons an acquaintance to death. He makes no attempt to hide the evidence, and the next day he returns to the scene of the crime along with some mutual friends of the victim. As they arrive at the victim's home, Rocky sees that the police have already discovered the body. Although it could have placed Rocky at great risk of criminal prosecution, he freely admits to having been alone with the victim on the previous day. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Rocky killed the person on the very day that an earthquake occurred. This made the person's death appear to be an accident caused by the natural disaster."
    },
    "Express Checkout": {
        "question": "Barry notices a boy and his father in a grocery store, neither of whom he has ever seen before. Although he doesn't speak to anyone and there is nothing unusual going on at the time, he calls the police moments later. What compels him to make this call?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Barry was purchasing milk and happened to notice the picture of the boy on the carton in his shopping basket. The cap- tion stated that it was believed the boy had been abducted by his father. The strong resemblance between the boy and the adult convinced Barry to call the authorities."
    },
    "The Debating Club": {
        "question": "Four longtime friends share a passion for debating. They have met every other Saturday night for the past ten years. There are periodic interruptions in their conversations that last a few minutes. This happens regularly, yet no one thinks twice about it and their debates always continue to a satisfactory conclusion. Can you explain these odd interruptions?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Each member of the group spoke only two languages, as follows: Sam speaks German and Spanish Jose speaks Spanish and French Pierre speaks French and English Joe speaks English and Japanese The interruptions occurred when someone, acting as the interpreter, needed to consult a bilingual dictionary."
    },
    "Bill's Birthday Surprise": {
        "question": "Marion's husband, Bill, was a slob who avoided bathing at all cost. On his wife's birthday, Bill decided to surprise her by taking a bath without having to be asked. Instead of being pleased, Marion was upset. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "After hearing of an impending flood, Marion scrubbed her bathtub and filled it with water to be saved for drinking. Unaware that the city's water had already been shut off, Bill used the water to take a bath."
    },
    "The Phoned-in Message": {
        "question": "Kathleen used the courtesy phone in the lobby of the hotel to call the hotel's front desk and leave a message for her husband. It would have been easier for her to walk to the front desk and leave the message in person. Why did she choose to use the phone?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Kathleen suspected her husband was staying at the hotel with another woman. Knowing the desk clerk would not divulge her husband's room number, she called from the lobby phone and watched to see in which box he placed the message."
    },
    "Making The Grade": {
        "question": "Alphonso was taking an important exam. Although the examiner was standing twenty feet away and had his back turned, he interrupted Alphonso by saying, \"You can stop right now, I know you are cheating.\" What led to Alphonso's undoing?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Nell could not hand in a postcard with her term paper because, although the paper was not due for another week, she had already handed it in. She was then free to write other term papers and study for exams in other courses."
    },
    "Something's Up": {
        "question": "A man suspected his wife of having an affair. He confronted her, but she claimed to have spent the entire day at home by herself. She had taken care that no items were left behind by her lover, but her husband soon found the only clue he needed to prove to himself that his suspicions were justified. What did he find?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "When the man went to use the bathroom, he noticed that the toilet seat had been left up. The man had been \"trained\" by his wife to always lower the seat, but apparently her lover had not yet \"learned\" this lesson."
    },
    "Mourning Gloria": {
        "question": "Gloria attended the funeral of a total stranger. She did not play any part in the funeral. In fact, the funeral would have taken place in exactly the same manner without her presence. Why did she attend?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Gloria was a lawyer who was looking for new clients. She hoped to approach the dead man's relatives in an attempt to bring a lawsuit against the drunk driver who had caused the victim's death."
    },
    "The Cinema Sneak": {
        "question": "After three attempts, Larry was finally able to sneak in the back door of a movie theater, and began watching the movie which had just started. After a few minutes, he left. Later in the week, he paid to see the same movie. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Larry had managed to sneak into a movie that was being shown in 3-D. Larry lacked the necessary glasses required to get the full effect, so he left and returned later in the week."
    },
    "Bad Medicine": {
        "question": "Mel had consultations with Dr. Greenwood over several days in an attempt to cure his condition. When Mel was finally cured, he immediately strangled the doctor to death. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mel was suffering from amnesia. When he searched his pock- ets for a clue to his own identity, he found Dr. Greenwood's name and address written on a scrap of paper. He assumed that he had previously made an appointment with the doctor to help cure his amnesia. Although no appointment had been made, the kindly doctor helped Mel overcome his problem. When Mel was finally cured, he remembered that he had been hired as a hit man to kill Dr. Greenwood."
    },
    "The Letter": {
        "question": "Danielle is eagerly awaiting the arrival of a very important letter. The letter contains vital information that could possibly save her life. Yet when it arrives, Danielle does not read the letter and in fact never even opens it. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Danielle feared being convicted of a felony crime. Since she possessed vital information that would clear her name, she sent the evidence to herself via registered mail. The date she received this evidence was crucial, so she left the letter intact."
    },
    "The Poem": {
        "question": "After reading a lengthy poem, a man realized that it had been originally written in another language. Although he had no prior knowledge of the poem or the poet, how did he come to this conclusion?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man had been translating several poems from various languages into Spanish. While translating this one particular poem, he noticed that it rhymed. He therefore concluded, correctly, that it had been originally written in Spanish."
    },
    "Finders Keepers": {
        "question": "One day, Ted finds a solid gold letter opener along the side of a busy highway. Although he is poor and would gladly pawn it for money, Ted knows that he will not be able to do so. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Ted was working on a chain gang when he found the letter opener. He knew that he would be searched and the item confiscated before he was placed back in his prison cell."
    },
    "Jury Duty": {
        "question": "In most states, a jury must vote unanimously in order to render a verdict of guilty. In this particular case, when the final vote was taken, one of the people in the room did not vote. However, the defendant was found guilty. How is this possible?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "One of the jury members was deaf, and required an interpreter to help him communicate. The interpreter was the one person who had no vote."
    },
    "Peculiar Parking": {
        "question": "Sam is a truck driver for Consolidated Freight Lines. His route takes him from Baltimore to Cleveland; Cleveland to St. Louis; then back home to Baltimore. When Sam is in Cleveland he always takes up two extra parking spaces before going to sleep in his truck. In St. Louis, however, he only uses one space. Why would he do this?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Sam's religion requires him to have his head facing directly north while sleeping. In order to accomplish this, he must sometimes park his truck in more than one space."
    },
    "A Golden Opportunity": {
        "question": "Bill challenged his friend to retrieve a heavy gold coin from the center of a bucket which had been half filled with dried peas. He then set forth the following rules: 1. No peas could be touched or removed. 2. The bucket could not be damaged in any way. 3. Nothing could be placed in the bucket other than one's hand. How did his friend meet the challenge?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Bill's friend placed the bucket on a potter's wheel and activated it. Centrifugal force uncovered the coin, pushing the peas to the side of the bucket. It was then a simple matter to grab the coin from the center of the spinning bucket."
    },
    "Diamonds Are Forever": {
        "question": "An eccentric billionaire bought a two-million-dollar diamond. He took it to the world's foremost safe maker and had him seal the diamond inside a seamless steel box. He then announced: \"Whoever can remove the diamond from the box without taking the box from this room or using any tools whatsoever can keep the gem.\" After years of attempts, how did one man succeed in this quest?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man shook the box back and forth, knowing that the diamond would eventually wear a hole through the steel."
    },
    "The Singing Kidnapper": {
        "question": "Kidnapper Karl would always sing his demands to the police. Why did he communicate in this strange way?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Karl's speech was hindered by severe stuttering. Knowing that the police would attempt to trace the telephone calls he made, he realized that he needed to keep his messages as brief as possible. Instead of speaking, Karl therefore chose to sing his ransom demands, because he never stuttered while singing."
    },
    "Dead Connection": {
        "question": "One night, two men committed suicide within minutes of each other. They had never met, nor did they even know of the other's existence. Yet, if the first man had not taken his own life, the other might still be alive as well. Why should this be so?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The first man worked as the sole operator of a suicide hodine during the evening shift. When he received the news that his wife had just been killed in an automobile accident, he decided to end his own life. The second man was contemplating suicide and tried to call the suicide hotline. Getting no answer, and having nowhere else to turn, he took his own life as well."
    },
    "Language Skills": {
        "question": "For most Americans, the inability to read and write in their native language would preclude them from working for the U.S. Government. Yet, at one point in our history, certain individuals with this trait were highly sought after. Who were these individuals and why did Uncle Sam want them?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "During WW II, the U.S. military tried to thwart enemy efforts to decode secret messages. They therefore employed Native American Navajo Indians. Their language has never been written down, and contains many subdeties, making it difficult to comprehend without actually having lived among them."
    },
    "It's About Time": {
        "question": "Reginald took great pains to locate and to go to a renowned clock maker where he purchased a clock which was purported to remain accurate to within one second per month. Reginald gently transported the clock to his study and mounted it securely on the wall. Later, Reginald brought the clock back to the shop and complained that it had lost over three minutes in less than a month. On hearing the story, the clock maker replied, \"But you never told me where your study was located!\" Why would that matter?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The study was located on Reginald's ship. The rolling motion of the waves caused the clock's pendulum to swing erratically, making the clock inaccurate."
    },
    "Fast Food": {
        "question": "Mike lives in a sparsely populated rural area. His commute to work takes an average of 70 minutes each day. Likewise, at the end of his shift, Mike spends an average of 70 minutes returning home. Considering the fact that Mike's lunch break is only 30 minutes long, how does he manage to spend it in the comfort of his own home?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mike's home was located on a small point of land at the mouth of a bay. His office was located on the opposite shore, a mere 300 yards away. On his way to and from work, Mike had to drive completely around the bay, a distance of sixty miles. Mike took his lunch break at low tide, at which time he could walk the short distance to his home."
    },
    "The Love Note": {
        "question": "Every morning, Victoria would wake up to find a love note left behind by her thoughtful husband, Mark. One morning, after looking and failing to see the expected note, Victoria despondently began to prepare for work. A few minutes later, Victoria was pleased to find Mark's amorous message in plain view and in a very conspicuous location. Why hadn't Victoria noticed it earlier?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mark had written the note on the bathroom mirror with his finger, while it was still fogged up from the shower he had just taken. He knew that the condensation would soon evaporate. This left an invisible message for his wife which she would clearly see after having taken her shower."
    },
    "Sticky Fingers": {
        "question": "Joan felt comforted by how routine her life had become. Even her packed lunch never varied from day to day. Imagine her dismay, when someone began stealing her meal from the lunchroom refrigerator. To make matters worst, the thief would taunt her by placing the empty bag back in the refrigerator. Joan finally devised a plan to reveal the culprit, without changing the contents of her lunch. How did she finally nab the thief?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Joan vigorously shook the can of soda in her lunch bag. When the thief opened the can, he received a well-deserved shower of soda, which marked him as the perpetrator."
    },
    "The Evidence": {
        "question": "Little did Ken know, that by merely walking into the room, he had just enabled a notorious mobster to be set free. How could this simple act have led to the release of a clearly guilty criminal?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Ken was the custodian at a police station. The red warning light, mounted outside the police photo lab, was not lit and Ken assumed that it was safe to enter the room. By opening the door, he ruined the pictures that were in the process of being developed. The pictures showed Bebe Bologna, the infamous mobster, committing a heinous crime. Later, it was discovered that the warning light had merely burned out."
    },
    "Creature Discomfort": {
        "question": "While traveling down a dark and lonely road, Bart heard a rustling noise coming from the woods. In an attempt to frighten away whatever creature lurked close by, Bart threw a rock in the general direction of the noise. The rock scored a direct hit. Although Bart succeeded in scaring away the animal, he regretted his choice of actions. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Bart had the unfortunate luck to strike a skunk. The skunk promptly released a foul-smelling spray that ended up ruining his clothes."
    },
    "An Alarming Change Of Pace": {
        "question": "William makes his living by cutting in front of people while they are standing in line and by setting off alarms. He does not work alone, yet he rarely talks to any of his colleagues. How does William earn a living?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "William and his co-worker, Tim, are thieves. Their scam took place at an airport. William would cut in front of a traveler who had just placed an expensive-looking item on the x-ray conveyer belt. William would intentionally set off the metal detector a few times by failing to remove loose change and other items from his pockets. Meanwhile, Tim, who had already passed through the metal detector, would grab the expensive item and make his getaway."
    },
    "Welcome, Slasher": {
        "question": "Bob, a fifteen-year-old boy with a record of violent crimes, approached a screened porch. Taking out a switchblade, he cut through every screen panel with large diagonal rips. A police officer drove by in a patrol car, saw what the boy was doing, and was pleased. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "A hurricane emergency had been declared, and poorly constructed buildings were at risk of major structural damage. Screens imposed wind resistance which could stress buildings enough to wreck them. Removing screens from screened porches was correctly announced as a safety measure, even if the screens were permanently stapled in place, so the boy had an opportunity to divert his destructive tendencies to a good cause. The policeman knew that the frantic absent homeowners had requested the boy's help with this potential problem."
    },
    "Smashed Taillights": {
        "question": "Later, Bob picked up a tire wrench and smashed the taillights of a car that he had never seen before. Police officers witnessed his act and arrested not him, but the owner of the car. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Bob had been kidnapped and locked in a car trunk. Aware of police department recommendations, he fumbled for the tire wrench and, having loosened it from its storage brackets, broke the taillights and side markers from inside. Then he was able to wave the wrench to passers- by and to call for help."
    },
    "Supposed To Kill?": {
        "question": "A man drew a gun, pointed it at another man who was known to be totally law-abiding, and pulled the trigger. Click! The gun wasn't loaded. Everyone present, which included at least ten people, was surprised and outraged. Why was the intended victim blamed for the incident?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "A scene was being filmed for a movie. For the protection of actors, it was universally agreed that anyone on the receiving end of a firearm had to load it personally with nonhazardous \"blanks.\" This particular actor had forgotten to load the gun, and the scene had to be refilmed."
    },
    "Burning Down The Building": {
        "question": "An old apartment building caught fire. Most apartments were damaged badly, and many people were left homeless. An investigator arrived from the fire department. A shady man pulled him aside into a dark corner of the building and handed him five hundred-dollar bills. \"It would be better for both of us,\" said the shady man, \"if something went wrong with the investigation. Lose the papers, or whatever.\" The investigator looked at the money and protested, \"But the landlord will want to file an insurance claim and need our report.\" \"He won't mind,\" the shady man replied. \"Be nice to other fire victims and don't ask questions.\" The investigator pocketed the money and conveniently forgot the case. Why did the landlord not get upset?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The landlord set fire to his own building. It was occupied by tenants who paid a low rent that was restricted by law. If they moved out, then he would have vacant apartments that could be offered at a much higher rent than before. Incurring fire damage was a sensible investment, for it would remove the low-rent tenants and permit elegant remodeling into luxury apartments that could fetch a very high rent."
    },
    "Caught In The Act": {
        "question": "A woman walked into a police station. \"I want to report a pickpocket,\" she announced. A man staggered in behind her, his hand in her coat pocket. \"Arrest that man!\" she continued, pointing to him. He was arrested, tried, and convicted of picking pockets. Why did he enter the police station in a posture that obviously suggested his crime?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "In this true story, a neighborhood pickpocket was caught by a woman, the wife of eighteenth-century inventor Peter Cooper, who sewed fishhooks into her coat pocket. When he caught his hand on the hooks, she told him, \"I am going to the police station, and you are coming with me.\" He cooperated to prevent serious injury to his hand."
    },
    "Slippery Sidney Slipped Up": {
        "question": "Slippery Sidney rented a car for a month. He returned it and paid the rental fee. Three months later, he was arrested for attempting to defraud the rental-car company. What happened?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Sidney was arrested for turning back the odometer and understating the number of miles that he actually drove. While at a distant city, he received two parking tickets from two different officers and didn't pay them. The city charged the fines to the rental-car company, and the company inferred that Sidney had driven the car there. But Sidney had not put enough mileage on the car, according to the odometer, to have been able to do so. The evidence was strong enough to convict him."
    },
    "Honest Ivan": {
        "question": "The rental-car company, after convicting Sidney, advised all personnel to watch for odometer tampering. Later, Ivan rented a car in central Florida. Two days later, it was badly damaged when a truck lost control and hit it on a thruway in Virginia. The odometer reading was too low to account for the trip from Florida to Virginia, but Ivan easily went free. How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Noting the much lower per-day cost of renting a car in Florida than in Washington, Ivan rented the car in Florida. He had it shipped from central Florida to a town in northern Virginia, where he retrieved it. The shipping cost was less than the total savings from renting the car in Florida and returning it to where he got it. By proving that he had sent the car by train, he convinced investigators that the odometer reading was genuine."
    },
    "Robbing The Bank": {
        "question": "Upon being tipped off that a large organization paid its employees on a certain day, and that its employees went to a specific bank to cash their paychecks at a certain time on that day, a gang decided to rob the bank at exactly that day and time. They would have been better off if they had robbed the bank on any other day than that one or at any other time during that day. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The organization was the local police force, and the numerous officers who were standing in line to cash their paychecks easily captured all of the would-be robbers."
    },
    "He Called The Police": {
        "question": "A burglar broke into a house, intending to steal from it. While still in the house, he called the police. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Once inside the house, he fell, breaking his leg. Pulling a telephone down from a table, he called an emergency police number for help and, though arrested, received treatment for his leg."
    },
    "Arrested Anyway": {
        "question": "Rocky Redneck carried a gun. He had a state-issued firearm permit that allowed him to do so, and he was careful to obey the law. One day, he went to visit his relatives across the country, in another state. Rocky had a firearm permit from that state, too; and he could legally carry his gun there. He found out from the airlines that he could take his gun with him if it was declared to the airline staff and was in checked baggage. Ever the law-abiding citizen, Rocky packed the gun in a suitcase, told the airline clerk about it, and had the suitcase checked. So why was Rocky arrested for weapons possession?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Rocky took one airplane to an intermediate stop, got out, and got into a second airplane to his final destination. If he had told the airline that he was doing so, then his fare would have been higher. He was trying to save money by noting that the fares for the separate parts of his trip were less than the equivalent fare for the whole trip. Therefore, he could not check the suitcase directly to the final destination, but had to retrieve it and re-check it at the intermediate stop. Rocky did not have a firearm permit for the state in which he made the intermediate stop, but was carrying the gun. He was arrested for that reason. Safe Smash-Up No one was in the car. It had been parked on a hill, and the driver who parked it forgot to set the brakes. Since the ignition was not on, there was no spark or other flame source to set fire to the fuel."
    },
    "No Ransom Demand": {
        "question": "A man entered a government building and went through a weapons-detector search. Then he entered a government office and displayed a sawed-off shotgun. \"Up against the wall, everyone!\" he ordered. Then, after everyone complied, he called the police. When police officers arrived, he put down his gun and cooperated with them. He refused to defend himself in court and was convicted of assault with a deadly weapon and given a long prison sentence. \"What's the point of taking people hostage if you don't make a ransom demand?\" asked a news reporter. \"I thought of making one,\" he replied, \"but there just didn't seem to be any point to it.\" So why did the man act as he did?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man was a cancer patient and was getting weaker and weaker. He had no medical insurance and would soon need hospital care. Confined to a wheelchair, he sat on the gun as he entered the government building. He threatened people in a room next to the district attorney's office so that he would be apprehended as quickly as possible, and he happily went to prison. He knew that, while he was a prisoner, the government would pay his medical expenses and that life as a hospital patient is essentially identical with or without serving a prison sentence. Contagious Carsickness? Stan had, as he had planned, stopped the car on a ferry boat. Jan became seasick."
    },
    "Escaping The Kidnappers": {
        "question": "Brenda had been kidnapped. She was locked in a room and placed on the floor, hands tied behind her back. She knew where she was, but had no chance of escape. Or did she? A telephone was on a table. She waited until no one was nearby, then she pulled the telephone to the floor. Alas! A dial lock! What did she do?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "A dial rapidly breaks and reconnects the telephone circuit. When you dial a number, you make the dial spin at a controlled rate and temporarily break the circuit that number of times when the dial is released. Without access to the dial, Brenda placed her fingers on the telephone switch-hook (where the handset is placed when the phone is hung up) and removed them rapidly exactly ten times, dialing \"0\" so as to reach the operator. The operator quickly connected her to the police department."
    },
    "Hearing Them Quickly": {
        "question": "\"Hey, Pop! Can I have some money?\" asked Dana. \"The Electric Earsplitters are giving a concert here in town next week, and I really want to hear it.\" His father put down the television listings, turned off the TV, and firmly declined. \"But that's my favorite group!\" protested Dana. \"I want to buy tickets real fast so I can hear them perform as soon as possible.\" \"If that's what's most important to you,\" replied his father, \"then you won't need any tickets.\" Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The father had noticed the planned live concert and noticed that it was also to be on television. Microphones would be a few feet from the performers and would capture the sound for television transmission. The audience, potentially including Dana, would be farther from the performers than the microphones would be. Sound travels at about 800 feet per second. Television waves and the electric currents that create and respond to them travel over a million times faster than sound. The father correctly figured that the television audience would hear the performance sooner than the live audience, for there would be less delay while sound waves travel the short distance to the microphones and from TV speakers to viewers than while sound waves travel the full distance from performers to the live audience. The difference is only a fraction of a second, but the father was nevertheless telling the truth."
    },
    "Motorcycle Madness": {
        "question": "Together, Peter and his brother Jamie owned some land in the country. They enjoyed outdoor activities on it, but lately had had trouble with motorcyclists who ignored the fences and no-trespassing signs and noisily rode where they wished. One day, Jamie and his wife Amy were outside, peacefully eating a picnic lunch, when two people on a motorcycle cut through the grass and raced past them. Jamie jumped up and ran to his car to chase them, when Peter drove up in his jeep. \"They went that way!\" shouted Jamie, pointing. Peter gunned the motor in hot pursuit. \"Did you catch them?\" Amy asked them later. \"No,\" replied Peter. \"They slipped through a gap in the fence and escaped.\" Why was Amy pleased?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Amy knew that the official penalty for trespassing was merely a small fine. She reasoned that, unable to identify Peter or know whether or not he was armed, the motorcyclists might count themselves lucky to have escaped apparent great danger and would spread the word that that piece of land was unfriendly, thereby encouraging others to stay away. A Token Wait in a Token Line Smart Stephanie observed that most commuters bought tokens as they entered the subway from the street. She merely bought tokens as she left the subway, when few other commuters did so."
    },
    "A Crying Problem": {
        "question": "Sandra had problems with her husband and was on strained terms with his parents. Nevertheless, one day she called them and chatted for about fifteen minutes. They thanked her for calling and told her that they felt better about her after talking. When she hung up the telephone, she burst into tears. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "After she and her husband had a particularly nasty argument, he had stormed out. She suspected that, as he had done previously, he had returned to his parents. Therefore, she called them hoping that they would tell her where he was. When they did not, she became very upset."
    },
    "She Never Fixed Him Up": {
        "question": "When Mitch started working in the small office, he was noted for his shyness. Anna, a co-worker, found out about his recent divorce and offered to set up a blind date for him. Eager to establish a new social life, he accepted her offer. But she never followed up on it, and he never met anyone else. Why did Mitch not mind?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Mitch and Anna got married and lived happily ever after."
    },
    "Happy That She Cursed Him": {
        "question": "A man called the woman he loved, and she cursed at him and hung up angrily. Why was he happy?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "She was married to another man, and he suggested that she pretend that he was an obnoxious telephone solicitor if he called while her husband might overhear. His ruse apparently worked, and he was pleased."
    },
    "Evicted": {
        "question": "A man locked his son out of the house. The son thanked him. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The son, in his late teens, was spoiled and idle. The father correctly inferred that evicting him and forcing him to earn his own way would benefit him, however unpleasant it would be at first. When the son found a job and had worked at it for a while, he understood how his father's action had made his life more respectable and constructive. Therefore, he thanked his father. What Drained the Battery? Walter, in a rush, forgot to turn off the headlights. No one else entered the parking lot until lunchtime, when managers customarily went out to eat. One of them turned off Walter's headlights, although by then the battery didn't have enough power to start the engine."
    },
    "Driving The Wrong Car": {
        "question": "Hermie the Hermit had a car that needed repair but was still drivable. He had another car that worked. He drove the first car to a repair shop. To avoid asking someone else to drive him home, he had fastened his two cars together and towed one with the other. He therefore arrived at the repair shop with two cars instead of one and could easily drive away with the working car. But why did he tow the working car with the broken one, and not the other way around? Clues: 47/Answer: 90. Safe Smash-Up A car slowly started to move forward. Then it picked up speed. Faster and faster it went, until it crashed through a guardrail and went over a cliff. It fell over a hundred feet and was badly damaged. No one was killed or injured. In fact, no one was even afraid of being killed or injured. Why not? Clues: 47/Answer: 92. Contagious Carsickness? Stan and Jan were driving along a highway. Fran, a small child strapped into the back seat, said \"I feel sick.\" \"It's probably carsickness,\" replied Jan. \"We'll be stopping soon,\" said Stan, \"then you can get out for some fresh air.\" Less than ten minutes later, Stan shut off the engine and they all got out of the car. But within half an hour, Jan complained: \"Fran has motion sickness, and I do, too.\" Jan did not normally get carsick. What was happening? Clues: 47/Answer: 76. What Drained the Battery? Walter forgot to allow for the slowness of traffic in the rain and was late for work. He hurriedly drove into the parking lot, parked, turned off the windshield wipers, jumped out of his car, slammed the door, and ran for the main entrance. That evening, he could not get the car started. The battery was dead. He got a jump start from a co-worker, drove home, and used his battery recharger to put a good charge on the battery. But despite careful testing, he never found out why the battery went dead. Can you?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The battery on the broken car was dead, and Hermie knew that the electrical system was suspect. He wanted the car checked thoroughly. He jump-started it with the working car, after which it could be driven. The working car had a manual transmission and could be towed without transmission damage. But the jump-started car had an automatic transmission, which is affected by towing. Hermie, therefore, towed the car that had the manual transmission. Spaced-Out at the Computer First solution: If you know the maximum number of spaces in a row, take the exponent of the next highest power of 2 and enter the command to replace two spaces with one space that number of times. (Example: seven spaces maximum. Next highest power of two is eight, which is 2x2x2, so use the command three times.) Second solution: Choose two characters that are never adjacent in either order (in this example, &%). First command: replace each space with &%. Second command: replace each %& (reverse the order of the characters) with nothing (delete %&). Third command: replace each &% with space."
    },
    "Seasonal Mileage": {
        "question": "Claude gets noticeably better mileage while driving the last mile to or from work than he does during any other part of the trip in summer. But not in winter. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Claude uses the air conditioner during summer. Just before the end of a trip, he turns it off so as not to waste fuel. He does not want to pay to keep the car cool while he is not in it. He is sensitive to cold, however; and he keeps the heat on whenever he needs it in winter, including when he is just about to get out of his car."
    },
    "She Arrived On Time": {
        "question": "Daryl and Carol had arranged to meet at a coffee house but something came up. Daryl looked in the phone book, found Carol's home phone number and called her. \"I know we were supposed to meet in the coffee house in two hours, but my boss called and I have to reschedule. I'm due at the office two hours from now.\" \"That's too bad,\" replied Carol, \"but I can meet you at the coffee house in two minutes if you'd like.\" Daryl agreed and, because he lived right across the street from it, was there in two minutes. He was content to wait, but Carol was waiting for him. \"You live clear across town,\" noted Daryl. \"How could you get here so fast?\" Clues: 49/Answer: 80. A Token Wait in a Token Line Smart Stephanie worked in a city and took the subway to work every morning during rush hour. In the evening, also during rush hour, she took the subway home again. To use the subway, she had to put a subway token into a turnstile as she entered the station from the street. Although she was one of numerous commuters at those hours and had to stand in crowded subway cars, she never had to wait in a long line to buy tokens. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Carol was not at home. She had had her telephone calls diverted to her cellular phone and simply happened to be in the coffee house when Daryl called her."
    },
    "The Late Train": {
        "question": "Amanda got onto a train. After traveling about one thousand miles, she got off. She arrived at her destination forty-five minutes late. There had been no delays, and the train had picked her up on time. Why was it late?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "During the night, which was the last Saturday in March, the time was advanced from standard time to daylight saving time. The engineer gained fifteen minutes during the night, but the train was still late when Amanda got off it."
    },
    "Stubborn Steve": {
        "question": "Steve went to an office supply store and got a ream (500 sheets) of standard-size paper. \"We have a special today,\" a sales clerk told Steve helpfully as he carried the ream to the checkout counter. \"It's a better grade of paper than what you're carrying, and it's cheaper, too.\" Steve investigated and he discovered that the paper on sale was the same size, same color, and of a heavier weight than the paper he had in his hand. Used in certain printers or copiers, it would be less likely to jam than would the paper Steve had chosen. And sure enough, it was much less expensive. Why, therefore, did Steve decline the paper on sale and retain his original choice? Clues: 50/Answer: 86. Making the Grade Nervous Nell, a college student with a straight-A average, went into her professor's office. She told the receptionist she was worried about her grade on the final paper for her course. \"I want to be sure I pass this course,\" said Nell. \"Is there some way I can be notified of my final grade as soon as possible?\" The receptionist, sympathetic to her concern, replied, \"If you hand in a self-addressed stamped postcard with your term paper, the professor will write the grade for the paper and the course on it and mail it to you as soon as the paper is graded. That's much faster than waiting for a transcript.\" \"Oh,\" said Nell, \"but I don't think I can do that.\" Why not? Clues: 50/Answer: 88. Spaced-Out at the Computer A secretary was working at her computer. She had a chart loaded into her word-processing program and had to rearrange it. The hard part of her job was removing extra spaces. The word-processing program had a \"replace\" command. She could replace any sequence of characters with any other sequence, or with nothing at all. So how could she replace many spaces in a row with only one space? This is not the same as replacing all spaces with nothing, because then there wouldn't be the one space that she wanted.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Steve was going to use the paper in airmail letters to correspondents overseas. To save postage, he wanted paper as light as possible, even if it was expensive and occasionally jammed his printer."
    },
    "The Fast Elevator Trip": {
        "question": "Bill was nearly late for an appointment in a tall office building. He ran into the building, reached the elevators that led to the correct range of floors, pressed the button, and waited. After a tense few minutes, an elevator arrived and opened its doors to receive passengers. Why didn't he get on?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "When the elevator arrived, other people crowded into it; and Bill critically watched them push buttons for several floors. Bill figured that the elevator would stop at the most floors at which it could stop. Therefore, noting that another elevator was approaching, he decided to get onto it instead; for he would share it with fewer passengers while it made far fewer intermediate stops on the way to his appointment. Avoiding the intermediate stops was worth the wait."
    },
    "The Nonstop Elevator Trip": {
        "question": "Bill got to his appointment on time. \"I was worried about those elevators for a minute,\" said Bill, \"but I figured out a way to get here faster.\" Then he explained his reasoning. \"Never thought of that,\" said Jill, who worked there and greeted him, \"but if you just get in an elevator, it sure can take a long time. I have a way to beat the system, too.\" \"What's your way?\" he asked. \"I just get in, and when the elevator first stops, I get out,\" she replied. He couldn't figure out how that strategy would save any time. Can you?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The floor was at the top of one range of floors served by one group of elevators. Jill instead used the adjacent group of elevators, going to the lowest floor served by them, which was one floor above her floor. Then, after her nonstop elevator ride, she merely walked down one flight of stairs."
    },
    "Too Precise": {
        "question": "Mary and Jerry were working in an office. Jerry was writing something, and Mary looked over his shoulder. \"That's too precise,\" complained Mary. \"It should be more vague, harder to understand.\" \"That's crazy!\" replied Jerry. \"The entire philosophy of the business we are in is based on that kind of reasoning I know, but that's not being tolerated here!\" \"Yes, precision is our great strength,\" admitted Mary, \"and ordinarily I'd agree with you. But in this particular instance, no.\" Where were they?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "In a politician's campaign office. They were volunteers for a candidate who believed in straightforward platforms instead of vague speeches."
    },
    "Exceptionally Vague": {
        "question": "Mary heard Jerry out, explaining what he was writing, and easily agreed that it should be deliberately misleading. What was he writing?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "It was a label attached to a key to the politician's other campaign office. Keys are best labeled cryptically or so as to mislead, so that they will be easily used legitimately but will be worthless to someone who should not have them. Jerry insisted that the key to the other office, which was at the river, be labeled \"River Bank and Trust.\""
    },
    "The Hostile Voter": {
        "question": "Charlie received a telephone call from the office of a local politician. A fast-talking campaign volunteer explained the benefits of the candidate, including a lecture on his platform. Charlie asked if the volunteer was calling at the request of the candidate, heard the volunteer's answer, and announced firmly that he intended to vote for the candidate's opponent. Then he hung up. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Charlie heard an aggressive sales pitch about a candidate who supposedly believed in keeping government as unobtrusive as possible. The volunteer was engaged in a meddlesome act, that of telephoning voters at home. Because the candidate approved such intrusive actions, Charlie deduced that the candidate was not going to keep his word about an unobtrusive government and decided not to vote for him."
    },
    "A Mystery Fax": {
        "question": "When his private phone line rang and he picked it up, the business executive heard a loud, squealing noise. Why did he receive a fax call on his private line, a phone that was known not to have a fax machine connected to it?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Quietly interested in changing jobs, the executive arranged for a cooperative recruiter to try to fax him a blank sheet of paper when trying to reach him. If he could talk, then he announced himself over the fax signal. If not, he called the recruiter later when he could discreetly do so."
    },
    "Another Mystery Fax": {
        "question": "One of the executive's subordinates sent a fax to a colleague. The subordinate would have preferred to have merely called the colleague in an ordinary way, but instead handwrote a note and faxed it. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The executive, aware of how easy it is to communicate with outsiders for undesirable purposes, warned employees that calls would be monitored. A subordinate, aware of the difficulties of monitoring a fax message, bypassed the monitoring by faxing instead of speaking his personal messages."
    },
    "Problems With Personnel": {
        "question": "Raymond, a business executive in a large company, needed a department head. After placing a classified ad, he reviewed the responses sent on to him from the personnel department. When a colleague mentioned a potentially suitable friend of hers who was looking for work, Raymond tracked him down, interviewed him, checked references, and hired him. Then he complained vigorously to the personnel department. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Raymond, who was in charge of research, had requested and expected to hire someone with a master's degree. The applicant, who had a doctorate, was rejected by the personnel department because he didn't have a master's degree even though the doctorate was, in Raymond's opinion, preferable. The Empty Wrapper She had her two-year-old son with her. When her son got hungry, she got permission from a store manager to buy a sandwich at the delicatessen counter, give it to her son, and pay for it later at the checkout counter with the rest of her merchandise."
    },
    "More Problems With Personnel": {
        "question": "It's true that all the references checked out positively, and the interviewee was hired. But a few weeks later, the colleague who recommended him to Raymond showed up\u2014and the newly hired department head was fired on the spot. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The applicant had had a roommate who was transferred overseas and who had impeccable credentials, but he himself was less scrupulous. He applied for work and gave his former roommate's name, background, and references. He wrote to Raymond's colleague and asked about work; they had never met. When the colleague saw that her apparent friend was an impostor, she said so; and Raymond promptly fired him."
    },
    "Dismaying Dizziness": {
        "question": "Raymond finally got an honest department head and had her office redecorated, installing new wallpaper, a refinished desk, and a bright ceiling lamp. He had received complaints that that office was dark and dirty, and he had no wish to alienate a new employee without cause. Unfortunately, she complained of dizziness in her office. He entered it to investigate, and he got dizzy too. Neither of them was dizzy anywhere else. What was the problem?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The lamp was fluorescent, and the new wallpaper had closely spaced vertical stripes. Fluorescent bulbs do not glow steadily, but flash 120 times per second. When viewing vertical stripes in fluorescent light, the intermittent lighting can make the stripes seem to turn as you turn your head, when they really stay fastened to the wall. This inconsistency is disturbing and is what caused the dizziness. The simplest remedy is to use only daylight. A more practical solution is to replace the fluorescent lamp with an incandescent one."
    },
    "Giving Wayne The Boot": {
        "question": "Wayne was asleep when a boot crashed through his bedroom window, waking him up. Loud music came from the house next door, further irritating him. He jumped up, shook his fist at his neighbor's house, and shouted some obscenities toward it. \"It's three A.M.,\" he yelled truthfully. \"If you don't turn down that racket now, I'm calling the cops!\" The music persisted and Wayne did as he had threatened and called the police. When they arrived, the officers refused to prosecute for the noise, even though it was obviously excessively loud. After the police officers explained the facts to Wayne, he was happy to forgive not only the noise but also the broken window. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Burglars had cut the neighbor's telephone wire and broken into his house. In self-defense, he barricaded himself into an upstairs room and successfully provoked Wayne to call the police."
    },
    "Racing The Drawbridge": {
        "question": "Park Street included a drawbridge over a river. As its warning lights flashed, Clarence proceeded toward the bridge. The barriers were lowered, blocking the road. Clarence ignored them. The drawbridge itself opened, and Clarence gunned the motor and aimed right at it. But there was no collision. Why not?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Clarence was navigating a boat, and the drawbridge was opened to let it pass. Short-Lived Messages Yolanda has an IBM-compatible computer and an Apple computer and wants to transmit data between them. With only one modem and little technical knowledge, she sends the data to herself through an on-line electronic-mail service with one computer and receives the data with the other computer."
    },
    "Recycled Salt": {
        "question": "Can salt be recycled? How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Bread recipes customarily call for small amounts of salt. By vigorously kneading bread dough and working up a sweat, one can add previously eaten salt to the dough so that it will be eaten again. More Short-Lived Writing Erasing colored chalk from a blackboard. Yolanda is a teacher and sometimes draws diagrams on the blackboard using different colors of chalk. Erasing such diagrams leaves colored smudges on the blackboard. Yolanda discovered that scribbling over the colored smudges with white chalk and then erasing the scribbling helps to remove the colored smudges and, unlike wiping the blackboard with a wet rag, permits immediate re-use of it."
    },
    "Scared Of Her Shadow?": {
        "question": "Wacky Wendy, who lives in Florida, finds it particularly important, when she is driving and sees the shadow of her car, to roll down her window. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "She drives an old car, with taillight lenses that have not been cleaned from the inside for perhaps ten years. Sunlight shining on taillight lenses can make brake and turn signals nearly impossible to see, particularly with dirty lenses or the dim bulbs in very old cars. Hand signals, under those circumstances, are more easily seen. Florida law permits hand signals for sufficiently small cars, even if the taillights work."
    },
    "Picture The Tourists": {
        "question": "\"I have a manual focus camera,\" said Sherman Shutterbug to his friend Sal as they sat next to each other on a tour bus. \"Mine is autofocus,\" replied Sal. \"It's much quicker, because the camera measures the distance to whatever I'm photographing and focuses automatically.\" \"Then I think we'd better change places,\" said Sherman. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Sal's camera focused by measuring the distance to the object in front of it, which would be the window of the bus. Sal's pictures of objects outside the bus would, therefore, be badly out of focus. But autofocus does not work when the distance is very small. Sherman wanted Sal to sit close to the window, so that the camera would ignore it and focus for great distance and would take good pictures."
    },
    "The Mirror": {
        "question": "A mirror is mounted over the headboard of a bed. It is there because someone has a bad back. Explain. Clues: 55-56/Answer: 86. The Empty Wrapper A woman was at the checkout lane of a supermarket. She removed several items from her cart and put them on the conveyor belt that led to the cashier. The cashier noted their prices and passed the items along to be bagged. A perfectly ordinary process, but one of the items entered and passed along was an empty wrapper. The cashier realized that the wrapper was empty, but charged for it anyway. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "It is one of two mirrors, both made of special optical-grade glass to prevent eyestrain. The mirror that is not over the headboard is mounted, on a flexible bracket, near it. After adjusting the second mirror, one can lie on one's back and look in it and see the reflection from the first mirror. By looking through two mirrors, one sees an unreversed image. This arrangement is useful for someone with a bad back who wants to lie in bed and watch television, for one need not be propped up but can lie truly flat."
    },
    "Secret Fuel": {
        "question": "Marvin often sneaked into his neighbor's driveway in the middle of the night in the course of playing a prank. He would quietly unscrew the fuel cap from his neighbor's car and pour gasoline into its fuel tank. What was he up to?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Marvin's neighbor had recently bought an extravagant sports car and bragged about it constantly. Hoping to quiet him down, Marvin poured a gallon of fuel into its fuel tank every few nights. After the neighbor began to boast about his new car's outstanding mileage, Marvin knew that his plan would work: merely add fuel quietly, then stop and let the neighbor wonder why the mileage suddenly deteriorated just as the warranty expired."
    },
    "Forgot To Stop?": {
        "question": "Angus was driving along a road at about thirty miles per hour. Suddenly, he jumped out of his car. He had not applied the brakes, and the car was still moving. He was not a stunt man for a movie or otherwise involved in deliberately risky activity. What happened? Clues: 56\u201457/Answer: 84. Short-Lived Messages Yolanda regularly writes and destroys messages to herself. Usually, people write such notes as reminders, such as in calendars. But Yolanda never expects to forget what was in the messages. Why write them? Clues: 57/Answer: 78. More Short-Lived Writing Yolanda often passes a writing instrument across a surface for which it is intended and, within a few seconds, erases the result. What is she doing?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The car ran off a bridge and fell into a lake, and Angus jumped out just as the car hit its surface."
    },
    "The Mail Is In!": {
        "question": "One day earlier, little Oscar had mailed an order form for a wanted toy Now, he was constantly pestering his mother to let him check the mail. Suddenly, looking out the window at the apartment complex mailboxes, he shouted, \"The mail is in! The mail is in!\" Neither he nor his mother had seen a mail carrier, mail truck, or any activity near the mailboxes, but Oscar was right, it was in. How had he known?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Oscar knew the procedure for receiving a package by mail. You take the key from your mailbox, unlock the pod, and take the package from the pod. The key stays in the pod door. Only a mail carrier can remove a key from a pod door. When Oscar saw a pod without a key and remembered that the pod had had a key on the previous day, he knew that the mail carrier had delivered the day's mail."
    },
    "Magazine Subscriptions": {
        "question": "Magazines often contain postcards meant for use by new subscribers. Some people consider them a nuisance and just toss them out. Some don't, even though they won't ever use them for their intended purpose. Why not throw them away?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Postage for a first-class item with a reply-paid address must be paid by the recipient. City residents may hoard the cards in case of a garbage collectors' strike, perhaps believing that those who contribute to the garbage problem should help solve it at their own expense. Dots on the I's A small I has one dot over it. A small I with a dot over it, therefore, actually has two dots, one above the other. Timmy took a pen and put two dots on his forehead, one over each eye."
    },
    "Soliciting In Seattle": {
        "question": "Two friends, who lived in different well-to-do neighborhoods in Seattle, were conversing. \"Almost every week, I get a few people who knock on my door and ask for money,\" said one. \"Odd. That rarely happens to me,\" replied the other. But there is a good explanation for the difference. What is it?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "In Seattle, one building houses the headquarters of several charity canvassing organizations. They send workers out to collect money, and those workers usually walk from the building when they start canvassing and return to it on foot when they are finished. Only one of the friends' two houses was within easy walking distance of that building."
    },
    "It's A Dog's Life": {
        "question": "Fred and Jed saw a badly injured puppy. It had been hit by a car, and its left eye and part of its left front leg were missing. Fortunately, it had received competent treatment. A bandage covered what remained of its left front leg, and a patch was fastened over the left half of its face. Fred picked up the puppy and stroked it gently. It whimpered weakly as he put it down. \"Poor thing,\" said Jed. \"Look what it's been through.\" Fred nodded his head grimly. \"I know. But it will almost certainly be alive in a year. That healthy-looking dog over there won't,\" he added, pointing to a frisky dog that wagged its tail eagerly. What was Fred's reasoning?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "They were at an animal shelter, which had a surplus of unwanted pets and had to kill those that it could not give to willing owners. Fred knew that people were often more willing to adopt a disfigured pet than an intact one. The injured puppy was likely to be taken by a loving family, but the healthy dog had no special claim for compassion and was too old to bond to its owners as strongly as do young puppies. Therefore, Fred expected the older dog to be humanely killed."
    },
    "Not From The Usa": {
        "question": "Belinda Blabbermouth told a riddle. \"I am standing in a place where I can travel north, south, east, or west, and soon be in the USA. Where am I?\" After everyone gave up, she laughed, \"The USA, of course!\" After a few seconds, someone else spoke up: \"Not necessarily. The country I come from, for example.\" Where was he from? Clues: 59-60/Answer: 89. Dots on the I's \"The teacher marked you wro-ong,\" Jimmy sang out teas- ingly during school recess. \"You didn't put dots on all your I's!\" \"Is that so!\" countered Timmy. \"Betcha don't know how to draw a small I with a dot on it!\" he challenged. Jimmy did so, and Timmy looked defeated. A few moments later, Timmy retorted, \"Well, now I have dots over my I's and you don't!\" One glance at Timmy and Jimmy burst out laughing. So did Timmy. Half the class did, too. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Windsor, Canada, adjacent to Detroit, Michigan, is directly both south and east of parts of Michigan. It is north and west of other USA states."
    },
    "Power Failure": {
        "question": "While Horace slept peacefully, a transformer on the street burned out and stopped all electrical power to his house. The power was restored two hours later, while Horace was still asleep. He awoke the next morning and noted with annoyance that all of his digital clocks were blinking and needed to be reset. \"I hate power failures,\" he grumbled, as he carried his battery-powered watch to the VCR, the microwave oven, and other devices that needed to have their clocks reset. But Horace had no idea that the power had failed during the night, much less how long. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Power failures occurred often. Horace, therefore, did not bother resetting clocks every time the power was restored. When the power failed during the night, the clocks had not been reset from the previous power failure and looked unchanged in the morning."
    },
    "Afraid Of The Country": {
        "question": "\"The city is so hot and sticky during the summer,\" Willie said to his friend Nicolai. \"I've got a house in the country. Can you join me there next weekend?\" Nicolai smiled. \"Ah, the country. Like a farm?\" \"Yes, you could say that,\" continued Willie. \"It used to be a farm a long time ago.\" \"That's good,\" continued Nicolai. \"When I was a boy in Russia, I lived on a farm. There were cows and pigs, and they were like my friends. It will be good to go away from this hot city and be on a farm again.\" \"You'll like it. It's so peaceful there,\" said Willie, continuing. \"Nice and quiet. No cars. Not even animals.\" Nicolai suddenly stiffened, and stared straight ahead hardly breathing for close to a minute. \"No,\" he eventually whispered quietly, \"I cannot. Thank you for your lovely offer. I would like to, but cannot go.\" Why was Nicolai terrified at the thought of Willie's country house?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Nicolai was afraid of silence. While on a farm during World War II, he was exposed to the sounds of livestock. Under normal circumstances, farm animals move around and make noise from time to time. But when scared, they do not. They could hear German bomber airplanes when people could not\u2014and became silent. Silence, to Nicolai, meant that an air raid was imminent and that he would have to hide in the basement. Despite many decades since the war, Nicolai never recovered from his fear."
    },
    "Long-life Bulbs": {
        "question": "Eccentric Eric flipped an ordinary light switch in his living room. The lights went on, apparently in an ordinary way. But there was special hidden circuitry involved. He was right when he boasted, \"My lights are wired so that the bulbs last much longer than average. I rarely have to change them.\" Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Modern incandescent bulbs have a coiled filament that glows as current is passed through it. A coil, however, radiates and absorbs magnetic impulses as the current through it is changed. It thereby not only resists changes in current (the electrical equivalent of inertia), but also shakes slightly as the voltage changes. The voltage changes with alternating current between +166 volts and -166 volts and back again 60 times per second, placing mechanical stress on the filament. Eric merely used direct current, so that the filaments would not be shaken by voltage changes and would last longer for that reason."
    },
    "They Had A Ball": {
        "question": "Two men stood on a softball field and practiced throwing and catching just before a game. \"Over here! Over here!\" shouted Ned, slapping his fist into his mitt. Ted threw the softball to him. \"Good catch! Throw me a grounder!\" shouted Ted. Ned returned the ball by throwing it along the ground, as requested. \"Now a high one! Right here! Right here!\" Ted threw the ball high in the air\u2014and Ned ran about ten feet to his left, reached up, and caught the ball easily. \"Good arm, but your aim is a little crooked,\" he announced. \"No it isn't,\" replied Ted.\" \"So what's wrong with throwing the high ball right to where I was standing?\" retorted Ned. What indeed?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The two men were not alone. Ted saw a teammate behind Ned and feared that if Ned missed the high ball, then the teammate might be hit by it. A throw directly to someone's body was different, for it would at least be deflected if it was missed. Ted aimed his high throw so that if Ned missed the ball, it would not hit anyone. Appendicitis Since the earlier surgery, Zeke had remarried. Happy with the TV Ad The man was a political candidate running for a local office. Tipped off that his rival had bought a 30-minute infomercial time slot, he bought the minute just before it and broadcast a test pattern, hoping to induce television viewers not to continue watching that particular channel. The TV Obeyed Eager to show off his elaborate new equipment, Jake had friends over. Not only did he set up his videocassette player, but also he carefully reviewed the instructions for his television set, which included a timer that would turn it off a specified time later. He carefully set the shutoff timer to outlast the movie by a minute or two and, when the ad came on, saw a warning on the screen that the television would turn itself off in a couple of seconds. He knew that it would be shutting off immediately, so he shouted at the television set just for the fun of it."
    },
    "Ballpark Befuddlement": {
        "question": "Nine men stood together at the edge of a field. One of them watched a ball intently and swung at it. Missed! He took another swing. Whack! The ball sailed up and to the left. A third swing. Zoom! This ball soared up and directly forward, and the man was pleased. Why didn't anyone run to retrieve the third ball?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The nine men were practicing golf swings on a driving range."
    },
    "Overdue Payment": {
        "question": "Jim sent a payment on a debt every month. One month, he accidentally missed the deadline and got a warning. He was eager to pay as quickly as possible and feared that a mailed check might be delayed in the mail, but didn't want to pay extra for registered mail, overnight delivery, or anything else. How did he minimize the chance of a delayed payment?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Jim mailed a check for the late payment. Then he went across town and sent another check for the same amount. If either check was delayed, then the other would probably arrive quickly. He figured that it was unlikely that both checks, if mailed from separate places, would be delayed. And the creditor would have received the next payment early, so that Jim would not have to ask for a refund."
    },
    "Wrong Order": {
        "question": "Jim waited. Sure enough, he got a message that the payment had arrived as he expected. Then he got a telephone call from his creditor, who had a secretary with an unusual attention to detail. \"You sent next month's payment, too,\" said the secretary. \"I figured that the check with the higher number would be for next month, and the one with the lower number was for this month. But the higher-number check got here first.\" \"It's up to you,\" replied Jim, who didn't real- ly care as long as the payment had arrived. \"But although I wrote the other one first and mailed it first, I'm not surprised that it arrived later.\" Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "He put the lower-number check into a mailbox near his house. Then he drove to the post office and mailed the other check there. Because the second check did not have to wait for mailbox collection, Jim expected it to be delivered sooner than the first check."
    },
    "I've Got Your Number": {
        "question": "Kingfist, a bookie well known for aggressive collection practices, was pursuing Sam Skiptown, who owed him money. From a distance, he spotted Sam and quietly followed him to his house. The house was well guarded, with a burglar alarm system and a climbable but inconvenient fence. Kingfist made plans. Within a week, he called Sam and warned him: \"Pay now, or take the consequences.\" Sam was horrified. \"How did you get my number?\" he asked. \"No questions,\" ordered Kingfist. \"Let's just say I went to a lot of trouble to ask you nicely.\" Sam never figured out how Kingfist learned his telephone number, which was unpublished and known to only a few trusted friends. Can you?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Kingfist found the telephone wiring that led into Sam's house and put one pin into each wire. Then he connected a telephone to the pins and dialed a long-distance number that was sure to answer, carefully charging the call on a telephone calling card. A few days later, he called his long-distance carrier and asked about possible misuse of the card and named the number that he had called. He easily learned the number that he had called from. A Sweet Problem Diabetic ulcers. According to alternative-medicine practitioners, sugar is a good medicine to apply to skin ulcers, blisters, and other open sores. Strange Sounds Some movies in the 1980s had scenes in which someone was typing, but the sounds of the keys were unrelated to the motion of the typist's fingers. Nowadays, scenes of typing conceal the hands to prevent that error. Reverberations remain a clue, as when a person walks from the outdoors into a narrow corridor and the footsteps do not reverberate indoors. Another clue is the absence of a companion sound, as when several people are walking and only one set of footsteps is heard. Or when a horse-drawn cart is shown and horses' hoofs are heard\u2014but the cartwheels themselves are totally silent."
    },
    "Collecting Backwards": {
        "question": "Kingfist forced a debtor to write him a check. Then he took it to the bank to cash it. Why did he first deposit money in the debtor's account?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Not enough money was in the debtor's account for the check to clear. Kingfist merely found out how much money he needed to deposit for the check to be good, then deposited it and quickly cashed the check. This procedure reduced, although it did not eliminate, the debt."
    },
    "Better Late Than Prompt": {
        "question": "Kingfist was engaging in his usual habit of bullying a debtor into paying. \"You don't have the cash? I'll tell you what I'm going to do,\" explained Kingfist. \"Sign this contract, and I'll tear up this one you signed earlier.\" The debtor reviewed the contracts and saw that the old one was his original loan and the new one was for the same amount, but for smaller payments that added up to the same total as the old one. The new one, overall, meant that the debtor didn't have to come up with money as fast and actually had a lower interest rate. And the new contract had no penalties for late payment, including harassment rights, that were not in the old contract either. The debtor was happy to sign. \"Thanks!\" replied Kingfist. \"I'll be seeing you!\" And that's exactly what happened. Kingfist was delighted, and the debtor soon realized he had blundered by signing the new contract. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Kingfist knew that the payments on the original contract were higher than the limit at the small claims court. He restructured the loan so that he could sue in small claims court every time a payment was missed. A small filing fee would induce major inconvenience for the debtor, who would have to repay the filing fee also. By restructuring the loan, Kingfist avoided all collection expenses which he could not recover. The debtor knew that major credit problems would exist from multiple unpaid judgments and scrupulously repaid the debt. Inefficiency Pays Off An air conditioner. The models with the most cooling power have stronger motors and cost more than those with less power. But because they cool air substantially, only a small fraction of the air in a room needs to pass through the mechanism to cool a room by a specified amount. Most of the air in the room does not pass through the air conditioner as the room gets cool. What does pass through it is sufficiently cold to cool the entire room. But as temperature goes down, relative humidity goes up. The dissolved moisture in most of the air is not removed, and a too-strong air conditioner makes a room feel not only cool but also damp."
    },
    "The Debtor Paid": {
        "question": "Kingfist had trouble with another debtor. \"What can you do about it?\" was the debtor's attitude. \"The collection hassle is more than the bad debt is worth, and we both know it.\" But within two months, the customer paid the loan in full. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "He went to small claims court, got a judgment, and sold the loan, with its judgment, to a racist extremist group of an ethnic background different from that of the customer. The extremist group was happy to receive the right to harass legally someone of its least-favored race, exceeded the limits of the law in its enthusiasm, and scared the debtor into paying. Laws that restrict collection agents, those who are hired to collect money on behalf of someone else, do not apply to creditors directly. Selling a judgment at a heavy discount can therefore be a prudent business practice, for it bypasses the collection-agent restrictions and may scare other debtors into paying promptly."
    },
    "She Was In The Hospital": {
        "question": "Alan called the office where his wife worked. \"I'm sorry,\" came the reply. \"There was a bad accident on the highway a few minutes ago, and she's expected to be in the operating room for at least six hours.\" \"That's too bad,\" he replied. \"Can you ask her to call me when she gets out?\" Sure enough, about six hours later, Alan heard from his wife. Why was she not upset that Alan didn't visit her personally? Clues: 64/Answer: 81. Appendicitis Zeke and his wife lived in a rural area. One evening, his wife felt ill. Zeke called the local physician. \"Doc, I think my wife may have appendicitis,\" he explained. \"Nonsense! I took out her appendix myself five years ago,\" said the doctor. But Zeke's wife proved to have appendicitis. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "She was a recently hired trauma surgeon and was working in the operating room."
    },
    "Crossed Vision": {
        "question": "If your eyes are crossed, then you see worse than usual. But if your fingers are crossed, then you may be able to see better than usual. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "If you cross your fingers, then there will be creases at the joints that will allow a small amount of light to pass between your crossed fingers. By looking at objects through the gaps between your fingers, you will expose your eye to only those rays of light that went through one small space. By doing so, you will see a sharply focused image even without wearing eyeglasses. This fact is unimportant except to people who need strong eyeglasses, but who are not wearing them at a particular time. Time for Repairs When he first looked at his watch in the morning, it showed the time 10:01. Later that morning, it showed 11:11. During his lunch break, it showed 12:21. The rest of the morning, it did not show the correct time. Dilton was unknowingly wearing his digital watch upside down. The VCR Timers Jenny noted that the device was battery-powered and could be programmed to tell the VCR to record Benny's favorite show every night. But if the VCR wasn't plugged in, then it wouldn't record anything. Therefore, Jenny got two 24-hour timers and set them each to be on for 12 hours. She plugged one timer into the wall, the other timer into the first timer, and the VCR into the second timer. Because the first timer delivered power only 12 hours out of 24, the second timer would do a complete cycle in 48 hours. It would deliver power to the VCR during 12 of those 48 hours, and Jenny set the timers so that the 12-hour periods included the time of Benny's show during alternate nights. It was easy to plug the VCR temporarily into an ordinary outlet when playing tapes or for other purposes."
    },
    "Night Blindness Cure": {
        "question": "What two questions can cure some cases of night blindness, without formal eye examinations or blood tests? Clues: 65/Answer: 87. A Sweet Problem White, refined sugar is frowned on as a dietary supplement and is especially to be avoided by diabetics (other than as an emergency treatment for insulin overdose or similar problems) \u2014except for what?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "1. Do you get night blindness only when driving your car? 2. When did you last clean and aim your headlights?"
    },
    "Miracle Cures": {
        "question": "Some resorts and shrines are known throughout the world for providing effective treatments for conditions believed to be incurable. One explanation is divine intervention, a literal miracle. Another is faith and belief in the cure. A third is an unknown but potentially discoverable scientific explanation, such as an unidentified ingredient in springwater. What is a fourth?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "After pretending to have a serious back injury and collecting a large judgment, a malingering patient can go to a well-known source of miracle cures and pronounce himself recovered without leaving any evidence of fraud."
    },
    "Not A Trusted Doctor": {
        "question": "Cassandra and her boyfriend went to a lecture. At it, a doctor described a reputed cure for senility. \"Nonsense!\" said Cassandra. \"He is no more a doctor than I am.\" \"What do you mean?\" asked her boyfriend. \"He showed us his medical school diploma.\" What did she mean?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Cassandra, unknown to her recently met boyfriend, had completed medical school and was a licensed physician. She carefully hid her income- earning ability from men whom she did not know well because she did not want to be exploited. She was as much a doctor as was any other medical school graduate and was telling the truth. She considered the senility treatment worthless, and she said so."
    },
    "The Plumber's Pressure": {
        "question": "A plumber received a checkup in the doctor's office. \"You have high blood pressure,\" said the doctor, after measuring it with a cuff. \"You'll have to watch the salt and take blood- pressure medication.\" \"That makes no sense, Doc,\" replied the plumber. \"Didn't you tell me last visit that I had some- thing else the matter with me?\" \"Yes, I did,\" replied the doctor, \"and you still do.\" \"That's why I don't trust that pressure gauge of yours,\" said the plumber. Why was he skeptical?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "He had arteriosclerosis, which made his arteries more rigid than those of most people. Measuring blood pressure by compressing an artery and listening is unreliable if the artery is inflexible. The plumber recalled his use of pressure gauges while at work and the ineffectiveness of measuring water pressure in steel pipes by merely pinching them, and he very sensibly wondered if his blood pressure was really high. Staged Roulette The police chief had a crooked gambling joint raided and easily obtained a rigged roulette wheel for the show."
    },
    "Rx Lead Poisoning": {
        "question": "A doctor examined a new patient and identified the woman's ailment. Later, as they spoke, he filled in her records, including medical insurance coverage. Suddenly, the doctor said, \"In that case, I would suggest you go to an old building and eat some lead paint chips from its walls.\" Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Chelation with EDTA is the recommended treatment for lead poisoning, and most insurance companies pay for that treatment. It is also, according to many doctors, a useful treatment for atherosclerosis; but most insurance companies don't pay for it for that diagnosis. The doctor was unwilling to falsify a laboratory test, but craftily noted that the patient could be maneuvered into receiving appropriate treatment that would be insured without the necessity for making any false statements whatever."
    },
    "Long Walk For The Disabled": {
        "question": "A man had a serious accident and partially recovered from it. Previously, he was in good physical shape. Now, he was disabled, but not in a way that qualified him for handicapped parking rights. Instead, he often had to park farther from destinations than he did before the accident. Explain. Clues: 66-67/Answer: 81. Eccentric Electronics Happy with the TV Ad A man went to a television station and bought one minute's worth of advertising time. He handed a videocassette to the station manager and learned to the second exactly when his one-minute tape would be on the station. Just before the scheduled time, the man turned on his TV set, tuned it to the correct channel, and waited. At exactly the time for his ad, a test pattern came on. The sound, an intense pure tone, did not change for a full minute. The picture stayed the same, too. Then the man, pleased, turned off his TV set. Explain. Clues: 67/Answer: 83. Time for Repairs Dilton got a new digital watch and put it on his wrist. At work, he looked at the office clock and checked his watch. They showed the same time. Later that morning, he couldn't make sense of what his watch showed and decided to return to the store with it. But before lunchtime, he again noted that his watch showed the correct time. During his lunch break, he returned to the store. But the salesclerk to whom he showed the watch noted that it showed the correct time, and Dilton agreed that it did. Dilton was soon satisfied that he had a watch that worked perfectly. But the clerk neither opened it for repairs nor replaced it. Explain. Clues: 67/Answer: 85. Strange Sounds Modern movies, unlike those of half a century ago, are often made with picture and sound recorded at different times. Sound-effects technicians watch the picture and make the appropriate sounds, perhaps walking in place on a hard floor to generate the sound of footsteps. How can this method of recording sound be detected in the final movies?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "He injured his neck and could no longer turn his head far enough to drive backwards easily. Therefore, he favored parking spaces that he could enter and leave without driving backwards, even if they were a long walk from his destination. To warn away children when he was forced to drive backwards, he installed a warning-tone device on his back bumper and wired it to his backup lights. Worth Twenty Dollars Any Federal Reserve bank would have exchanged the $20 bill, but would have insisted that ordinary currency is legal tender in payment of debts and replaced it with another $20 bill. Unless the original bill was damaged by fire or otherwise hard to spend, there is little reason to make such an exchange."
    },
    "Watching The Game": {
        "question": "Elmer had a sports bar, one with several TV screens hooked up to a satellite receiver and tuned to receive popular sports events. One day, there was a ball game in a stadium nearby. The game was blacked out from the local television stations and even from local satellite receivers, but Elmer and his customers saw the game on television anyway. How? Clues: 68/Answer: 91. Digital Downfall Why do hi-fi enthusiasts sometimes dislike compact disks and other digital recording media? Clues: 68/Answer: 94. The TV Obeyed Jake had some friends over to watch a popular new movie on his brand-new big-screen TV with state-of-the-art surround-sound speakers. As the credits ended and everyone started to the kitchen for snacks, an obnoxious commercial came on. Jake turned to the set. \"Oh, shut up!\" he shouted angrily at the TV\u2014and it did! Explain. Clues: 68-69/Answer 83. The VCR Timers Benny and Jenny were busy hooking up a new videocassette recorder. \"I'll never understand these instructions!\" shouted Benny, as he tried to set the VCR timer to record his favorite show every other night. \"They make no sense to me, either,\" admitted Jenny. They returned to the store for advice and the salesclerk admitted that the instructions confused him too. \"I recommend this for most of my customers,\" he said, showing them a battery-powered device that looked like a VCR remote control unit. \"You can set it to signal start-recording and stop-recording for any time you want, once a week, every day, or whenever.\" Benny and Jenny looked through its instruction book and understood it easily. \"Great!\" said Benny. \"Now I can tape my favorite show every other night.\" \"No you can't,\" admitted the salesclerk. \"It won't let you do that\u2014just every night or once a week.\" \"Yes we can,\" replied Jenny. \"After a trip to the hardware store, that is.\" How?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Satellite signals are generally scrambled. To receive them in usable form, you buy an electronic device (a transponder) and pay royalties to the satellite company, which in turn sets your transponder to unscramble the appropriate signals. Elmer's accomplice ran a sports bar in a distant city and also had a transponder. To obtain unscrambled signals of locally blacked-out games, they merely swapped transponders. No Television Trouble A pocket-size television set was on top of the dashboard, and it was off. Stuart was listening to an audiocassette with his favorite show's theme music."
    },
    "The Vcr Remote Control": {
        "question": "After Benny and Jenny set up their VCR to record their show on alternate nights, Benny looked for the remote control to the other VCR in the bedroom. \"I put it away so the dog wouldn't get it,\" explained Jenny. \"That's a nuisance,\" replied Benny. \"Then we can't operate the VCR while lying in bed.\" \"Yes we can,\" replied Jenny. How? Clues: 69-70/Answer: 93. No Television Trouble Stuart was driving a car along a highway. A small television set sat on the dashboard, and Stuart could see its screen. The theme music from Stuart's favorite television show came on. At a police roadblock set up to screen and catch lawbreakers, a state trooper observed Stuart and his television set, but did not warn or arrest him. Why not? Clues: 70/Answer: 91. Inefficiency Pays Off A certain mechanical object is often made in several models by each of its manufacturers. Government regulations require that its retail sellers offer information that will allow part of the cost of operation to be calculated. Of a manufacturer, the models of the object offered can be ranked from least to most expensive. The cheapest model costs relatively little to buy and to operate and has simple controls. The most expensive model costs most to operate and generally has the most elaborate controls. But the most expensive model is not necessarily the one that is most effective at doing what it is designed to do. What is the object? Clues: 70/Answer: 93. Mad Money Worth Twenty Dollars Nick had a series 1950 $20 bill. Instead of saying \"Twenty dollars\" at the bottom, it said \"Will pay to the bearer on demand twenty dollars.\" He told his friend Dick, \"If I can get twenty dollars' worth of gold or silver, then I may as well exchange this bill at the Federal Reserve office that issued it.\" Was he right?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Except for the nuisance of long cables and a small loss of signal, there is no reason for a videocassette recorder to be close to a television set. Jenny merely moved the VCR to a shelf built into their headboard, where they could both easily reach it while in bed, and connected it to the TV with a long cable. Digital Downfall Non-digital media merely record the sound waves as heard. Sound waves consist of fluctuations in air pressure, and a microphone can translate those fluctuations to fluctuations in an electrical signal that is in turn stored on magnetic tape or on a vinyl disk. Digital recording, however, translates the fluctuations to signals that represent the amplitudes and frequencies of the various components of the sound. But those signals don't match the timing of the wave cycles properly, so that the different pure tones that constitute a composite sound may be recorded out of phase and sound different when played back than when first recorded. Partially for that reason, they don't properly record overtones, which are high-frequency sounds that result from two or more lower-frequency sounds in harmony."
    },
    "Slow-witted Customers": {
        "question": "In northern Florida, fast-food chains often have a pricing policy that works only because many customers do not think carefully. What is it?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The menus of the fast-food restaurants offer soft drinks in different-sized cups, labeled \"Small,\" \"Medium,\" and \"Large,\" with correspondingly different prices. Then the restaurants also offer unlimited free refills on the same soft drinks!"
    },
    "Banking On The Boycott": {
        "question": "On the principal street of a small town, a fast-food restaurant chain was planning to open. Local citizens, wary of litter and disruption, and eager to defend the livelihoods of their local diners, planned retaliation. At a town meeting, a woman urged strict enforcement of litter and parking-meter laws. A man stood up and suggested something more devious: that everyone go there and order something, but insist on a special order (no lettuce with the hamburger, etc.) so as to overwhelm the help. Another man, who happened to work at the town bank, approved of the action, but recommended that they all come to his place of business first. Why?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "As the first man suggested, a group agreed to place special orders and overwhelm the help. The second man's strategy involved unusual denominations of money. The first people to place special orders were equipped with fifty- and hundred-dollar bills to force the cash registers to run out of small denominations. By taking a bite out of food before offering to pay for it, the group members would force acceptance of their large bills. The next people in the group got Susan B. Anthony dollars, which are easily confused with quarters, and half dollars and two-dollar bills. These unfamiliar but legal denominations would not fit easily into cash registers and would confuse the cashiers, who would be out of ordinary denominations. Properly done, with angry customers demanding their change, this maneuver would force the chain to generate ill will and lose money."
    },
    "Old Money But Good Money": {
        "question": "What two changes affected U.S. currency in 1968 that, if considered together, scare certain conservatives?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "United States currency formerly included silver certificates, which stopped being redeemable for silver in 1968. Since then, there has been no formal precious metal backing to guarantee its value. The year 1968 was also the first year that denominations higher than one dollar suggested the fear of currency devaluations by carrying the words \"In God We Trust.\" Religious zealots favored the wording; some conservative economists took warning."
    },
    "Secret Business": {
        "question": "Two men were on the telephone, discussing a multi-million- dollar business deal. They used electronic scramblers, so that no one could easily listen in on their conversation. They also each had much more sophisticated scramblers, which were harder to obtain and which encoded conversations more securely than the scramblers that they used. Why did they use the less secure scramblers?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The men were planning a big business deal, and they were pretty sure that their telephones were tapped. They used a simple scrambler that could easily be obtained by an eavesdropper. But before the telephone conversation, they wrote a script for a fake conversation in which they discussed doing the opposite of what they really planned to do. They wanted eavesdroppers to anticipate the wrong plans and lose money, which the two men would gain. A secure scrambler would not have allowed eavesdroppers to hear the staged conversation and would not have helped the two men."
    },
    "Gas-station Glitch": {
        "question": "During a fuel shortage, George drove to a gas station and waited in line behind many other motorists. A man in the familiar gas-station uniform walked over and explained to him, \"We have a ten-dollar limit. To save time, we are taking cash only and collecting payment in advance.\" George gave the man a ten-dollar bill. When he reached the front of the line and parked in front of a pump, he asked for his ten dollars' worth of gas. \"The limit is five dollars,\" replied the attendant. What happened?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The man whom George paid was not an employee of the station, but a con artist who got a uniform, asked everyone in line for ten dollars, and left quickly."
    },
    "Marketing Muddle": {
        "question": "What carelessly marketed name of a car may provoke concerns about auto safety?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The Kia is marketed with the crossbar of the A missing: KIA. The A is the Greek-alphabet equivalent of our letter L, which means that USA customers who know the Greek alphabet may read K-I-L and wonder about the auto's safety."
    },
    "Easy Money": {
        "question": "The television set had a retail value of $100. Butch worked at the wholesale warehouse and said that stores bought them for $60 each. The warehouse bought them in large lots for $45 apiece. He offered to sell you all you want for $30 each. If they cost $45, then how could he make a profit at $30?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Butch stole the television sets from his employer, making a profit of $30 for each set that he sold."
    },
    "Too Much Money": {
        "question": "An investor was reading the description of a proposed investment. It was a limited partnership, so that the investor would have no control over the management of the investment. But there were safeguards in place so that if the person who managed the investment made a profit, then the investor would too. Suddenly, the investor discovered something that made him decide not to invest. \"Too much money,\" he muttered to himself, throwing the description onto his desk. Too little money invested in a company can be a bad sign, for it may go bankrupt. But why would the investor be afraid of too much money?",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "The investor was going to be a limited partner. Someone who invests in a company as a limited partner does not have the right to manage the company, not even partial or voting rights. Such an arrangement is common and completely legal and ethical. Without management authority, the investor wouldn't be concerned about losing control to other investors. What worried him were the personal finances of the people who were going to manage the company. They could have invested all of their money in it, but didn't. If they had a lot of money outside the company, then the investor feared that they expected the company to fail. Youthful Gamble College students, despite uniform room charges, are often assigned dormitory rooms of unequal sizes by lottery. Similarly, equal tuition payments do not necessarily result in equal education, because lotteries are used to select which students get access to popular courses that have enrollment quotas."
    },
    "Lottery Logic": {
        "question": "Many states run lotteries as a way to raise money. For every dollar received from lottery-ticket sales, perhaps half a dollar is paid out to winners. Therefore, the weighted-average value of the expected winnings of a one-dollar ticket is perhaps half a dollar. Therefore, although a lottery ticket may be a fun expense because it carries a chance to get rich, it is never a good investment from a financial-planning perspective. Right? Clues: 73-74/Answer: 89. Youthful Gamble Some people gamble irrationally and are at risk of losing more money than they can afford to. Laws exist, therefore, to prohibit gambling except under special circumstances. It would seem especially important to keep young adults from gambling, for bad habits can be formed while young that cannot be easily corrected later. But certain young adults are allowed to gamble, in that they pay money and receive something of greater or lesser value, in exchange for that money, that is partially determined by chance. Explain.",
        "difficulty": "Unsorted",
        "answer": "Lottery tickets or other risky investments are very sensible when bankruptcy is imminent. Suppose, for example, you have $10,000 in assets and $20,000 in liabilities. If you merely pay your debts to the best of your ability, then you are certain to go broke. But if you buy as many lottery tickets as you can afford, then you have a chance of winning more than what you owe. Then you would be able to pay your debts and have some money left over. Although winning a large amount of money is unlikely, it is possible. That possibility converts certain bankruptcy into a chance to be rich."
    }
}
